<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>im.kaidan.kaidan</id>
  <name>Kaidan</name>
  <name xml:lang="ar">كيدان</name>
  <name xml:lang="ca">Kaidan</name>
  <name xml:lang="ca-valencia">Kaidan</name>
  <name xml:lang="cs">Kaidan</name>
  <name xml:lang="de">Kaidan</name>
  <name xml:lang="el">Kaidan</name>
  <name xml:lang="en-GB">Kaidan</name>
  <name xml:lang="eo">Kaidan</name>
  <name xml:lang="es">Kaidan</name>
  <name xml:lang="eu">Kaidan</name>
  <name xml:lang="fi">Kaidan</name>
  <name xml:lang="fr">Kaidan</name>
  <name xml:lang="gl">Kaidan</name>
  <name xml:lang="he">Kaidan</name>
  <name xml:lang="hi">कैदान</name>
  <name xml:lang="id">Kaidan</name>
  <name xml:lang="ie">Kaidan</name>
  <name xml:lang="it">Kaidan</name>
  <name xml:lang="ka">Kaidan</name>
  <name xml:lang="ko">Kaidan</name>
  <name xml:lang="nl">Kaidan</name>
  <name xml:lang="nn">Kaidan</name>
  <name xml:lang="pl">Kaidan</name>
  <name xml:lang="pt">Kaidan</name>
  <name xml:lang="pt-BR">Kaidan</name>
  <name xml:lang="ru">Kaidan</name>
  <name xml:lang="sk">Kaidan</name>
  <name xml:lang="sl">Kaidan</name>
  <name xml:lang="sv">Kaidan</name>
  <name xml:lang="tr">Kaidan</name>
  <name xml:lang="uk">Kaidan</name>
  <name xml:lang="zh-CN">Kaidan</name>
  <name xml:lang="zh-TW">Kaidan</name>
  <summary>Modern chat app for every device</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ar">تطبيق دردشة حديث لكل جهاز</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ca">Aplicació moderna de xat per a tots els dispositius</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ca-valencia">Aplicació moderna de xat per a tots els dispositius</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="cs">Moderní klient pro rozhovory pro každé zařízení</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="en-GB">Modern chat app for every device</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="eo">Moderna retbabililo por ĉiu aparato</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="es">Aplicación de conversación moderna para todos los dispositivos</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="eu">Gailu guztietarako berriketa aplikazio modernoa</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="fi">Nykyaikainen keskustelusovellus joka laitteelle</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="fr">Application moderne de messagerie instantanée sur n'importe quel périphérique</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="gl">Aplicación de charla moderna para calquera dispositivo</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="he">יישום שיחות מודרני לכל סוג של מכשיר</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="id">Aplikasi chat modern untuk setiap peranti</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="it">Programma di chat moderno per qualsiasi dispositivo</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ka">თანამედროვე ჩატის აპი ყველა მოწყობილობისთვის</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ko">모든 장치에서 사용할 수 있는 현대적인 채팅 앱</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="nl">Moderne chat-toepassing voor elk apparaat</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="nn">Moderne nettprat-program for alle typar einingar</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pl">Nowoczesna aplikacja do rozmów na każde urządzenie</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pt-BR">Aplicativo de bate-papo moderno para todos os dispositivos</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ru">Современное приложение для работы с чатами на всех устройствах</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sl">Moderna aplikacija za klepet za vsako napravo</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sv">Modernt chattprogram för alla enheter</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="tr">Her aygıt için çağdaş sohbet uygulaması</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="uk">Сучасна програма для спілкування на будь-якому пристрої</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="zh-CN">适用于各种设备的现代聊天应用</summary>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0+</project_license>
  <description>
    <p>Kaidan is a user-friendly and modern chat app for every device. It uses the open communication protocol XMPP (Jabber). Unlike other chat apps, you are not dependent on one specific service provider.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ar">كيدان هو تطبيق دردشة حديث وسهل الاستخدام لكل الأجهزة. يستخدم بروتوكول الاتصالات المفتوح XMPP (Jabber). على عكس تطبيقات الدردشة الأخرى، لا تعتمد على مزود خدمة محدد.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca">El Kaidan és una aplicació de xat fàcil d'emprar i moderna per a tots els dispositius. Fa servir el protocol obert de comunicacions XMPP (Jabber). A diferència d'altres aplicacions de xat, no dependreu d'un proveïdor de serveis en concret.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">Kaidan és una aplicació de xat fàcil d'emprar i moderna per a tots els dispositius. Utilitza el protocol obert de comunicacions XMPP (Jabber). A diferència d'altres aplicacions de xat, no dependreu d'un proveïdor de serveis en concret.</p>
    <p xml:lang="en-GB">Kaidan is a user-friendly and modern chat app for every device. It uses the open communication protocol XMPP (Jabber). Unlike other chat apps, you are not dependent on one specific service provider.</p>
    <p xml:lang="eo">Kaidan estas uzebla kaj moderna babilejo por ĉiu aparato. Ĝi uzas la malferman komunikan protokolon XMPP (Jabber). Male al aliaj babilaj apoj, vi ne dependas de unu specifa servoprovizanto.</p>
    <p xml:lang="es">Kaidan es una aplicación de conversación moderna y fácil de usar para todos los dispositivos. Usa el protocolo de comunicación abierto XMPP (Jabber). A diferencia de otras aplicaciones de conversación, no depende de un proveedor de servicios específico.</p>
    <p xml:lang="eu">Kaidan gailu guztietarako berriketa aplikazio moderno eta lagunkoia da. XMPP (Jabber) komunikazio protokolo irekia erabiltzen du. Beste berriketa aplikazioekin ez bezala, ez zara zerbitzu-hornitzaile baten mendekoa.</p>
    <p xml:lang="fi">Kaidan on joka laitteen käyttäjäystävällinen ja nykyaikainen keskustelusovellus. Se käyttää avointa XMPP-viestintäyhteyskäytäntöä (Jabber). Toisin kuin muissa keskustelusovelluksissa, et ole riippuvainen tietystä palveluntarjoajasta.</p>
    <p xml:lang="fr">Kaidan est une application moderne et conviviale de messagerie instantanée pour n'importe quel périphérique. Il utilise le protocole de communication libre « XMPP » (Jabber). Contrairement aux autres applications de messagerie instantanée, vous n'êtes dépendant d'aucun fournisseur de services spécifiques.</p>
    <p xml:lang="gl">Kaidan é unha aplicación de charla moderna e amigábel para cada dispositivo. Usa o protocolo aberto de comunicacións XMPP (Jabber). Ao contrario que outras apps, non dependes dun provedor de servizos específico.</p>
    <p xml:lang="he">Kaidan הוא יישום שיחה מודרני ידידותי למשתמשים. הוא משתמש בפרוטוקול התקשורת הפתוח XMPP‏ (Jabber). בניגוד ליישומי שיחה אחרים, אין תלות בספק שירות מסוים אחד.</p>
    <p xml:lang="id">Kaidan adalah aplikasi chating yang mudah digunakan dan modern untuk setiap peranti. Aplikasi ini menggunakan protokol komunikasi terbuka XMPP (Jabber). Tidak seperti aplikasi chating lainnya, Anda tidak bergantung pada satu penyedia layanan tertentu.</p>
    <p xml:lang="it">Kaidan è un programma di chat amichevole e moderno per qualsiasi dispositivo. Utilizza il protocollo di comunicazione aperto XMPP (Jabber). A differenza di altri programmi non sei dipendente da uno specifico fornitore di servizi.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ka">Kaidan არის მოსახერხებელი და თანამედროვე ჩეთის აპლიკაციაა ყველა მოწყობილობისთვის. ის იყენებს ღია საკომუნიკაციო პროტოკოლს XMPP (Jabber). სხვა ჩეთის აპებისგან განსხვავებით, თქვენ არ ხართ დამოკიდებული ერთ კონკრეტულ სერვისის პროვაიდერზე.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ko">Kaidan은 모든 장치에서 사용할 수 있는 사용자 편의적인 채팅 앱입니다. 개방형 통신 프로토콜 XMPP(Jabber)를 사용합니다. 다른 채팅 앱과는 다르게 하나의 서비스 공급자에 의존하지 않습니다.</p>
    <p xml:lang="nl">Kaidan is een gebruikersvriendelijke en moderne chat-toepassing voor elk apparaat. Het gebruikt het open communicatieprotocol XMPP (Jabber). Anders dan andere chat-toepassingen bent u niet afhankelijk van één specifieke serviceprovider.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pl">Kaidan to przyjazna użytkownikom i nowoczesna aplikacja do rozmów na każdym urządzeniu. Używa otwartego protokołu porozumiewania się o nazwie XMPP (Jabber). W odróżnieniu od innych aplikacji do rozmów, nie jesteś zależny od jednego dostawcy tej usługi.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt">O Kaidan é uma aplicação de conversas amigável e moderna para todos os tipos de dispositivos. Usa o protocolo aberto de comunicações XMPP (Jabber). Ao contrário das outras aplicações de conversas, não está dependente de um fornecedor de serviços específico.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt-BR">O Kaidan é um aplicativo de bate-papo moderno e fácil de usar para todos os dispositivos. Ele utiliza o protocolo de comunicação aberto XMPP (Jabber). Ao contrário de outros aplicativos de bate-papo, você não depende de um provedor de serviços específico.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ru">Kaidan — удобное современное приложение для работы с чатами на всех устройствах. В программе используется открытый протокол обмена данными XMPP (Jabber). В отличие от других приложений для работы с чатами, работа этой программы не зависит от одного определённого поставщика услуг.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sl">Kaidan je uporabniku prijazna in moderna aplikacija za klepet na vsaki napravi. Uporablja odprti komunikacijski protokol XMPP (Jabber). Za razliko od drugih aplikacij za klepet, niste odvisni od enega samega ponudnika storitev.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sv">Kaidan är ett användarvänligt och modernt chattprogram för alla enheter. Det använder det öppna kommunikationsprotokollet XMPP (Jabber). I motsats till andra chattprogram är du inte beroende av en specific tjänstleverantör.</p>
    <p xml:lang="tr">Kaidan, her tür aygıt için kullanıcı dostu ve çağdaş teknolojilerle yaratılmış bir sohbet uygulamasıdır. Açık bir sohbet protokolü olan XMPP’yi (Jabber) kullanır. Diğer sohbet uygulamalarının aksine, belirli bir hizmet sağlayıcıya bağlı kalmazsınız.</p>
    <p xml:lang="uk">Kaidan — зручна для користування та сучасна програма для спілкування на будь-якому пристрої. У ній використано відкрити протокол для спілкування XMPP (Jabber). На відміну від інших програм для спілкування, ви не залежатимете від одного певного надавача послуг зв'язку.</p>
    <p xml:lang="zh-CN">Kaidan 是用户友好、现代的聊天应用，适用于各种设备。它使用开放通信协议 XMPP（Jabber）。与其他聊天应用不同，您不依赖于某个特定的服务提供者。</p>
    <p xml:lang="zh-TW">Kaidan 是一個友善且現代化的聊天應用程式，且支援任何裝置。它使用 XMPP (Jabber)，一個開放的通訊協定。如此，您不需依賴任何一個特定的服務提供者。</p>
    <p>Kaidan does not have all basic features yet and has still some stability issues. But we do our best to improve it!</p>
    <p xml:lang="ar">لا يحتوي كيدان على جميع الميزات الأساسية حتى الآن ولا يزال يعاني من بعض مشكلات الاستقرار. لكننا نبذل قصارى جهدنا لتحسينه!</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca">El Kaidan encara no té totes les característiques bàsiques i té alguns problemes d'estabilitat. Però fem tot el possible per a millorar-ho!</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">Kaidan encara no té totes les característiques bàsiques i té alguns problemes d'estabilitat. Però fem tot el possible per a millorar-ho!</p>
    <p xml:lang="en-GB">Kaidan does not have all basic features yet and has still some stability issues. But we do our best to improve it!</p>
    <p xml:lang="eo">Kaidan ankoraŭ ne havas ĉiujn bazajn funkciojn kaj ankoraŭ havas kelkajn stabilecajn problemojn. Sed ni faras nian eblon por plibonigi ĝin!</p>
    <p xml:lang="es">Kaidan aún no posee todas las funciones básicas y todavía tiene algunos problemas de estabilidad. ¡Pero hacemos todo lo posible para mejorarlo!</p>
    <p xml:lang="eu">Kaidan-ek ez ditu oraindik oinarrizko ezaugarri guztiak eta egonkortasun azaro batzuk ditu. Baina hori hobetzeko ahalegin guztiak egiten ditugu!</p>
    <p xml:lang="fi">Kaidanissa ei vielä ole kaikkia perusominaisuuksia, ja siinä on joitakin vakausongelmia. Mutta teemme parhaamme parantaaksemme sitä!</p>
    <p xml:lang="fr">Kaidan ne possède pas encore toutes les fonctionnalités de base et présente encore quelques problèmes de stabilité. Mais tout est fait de notre côté pour l'améliorer !</p>
    <p xml:lang="gl">Kaidan aínda non inclúe todas as características básicas  e ten algún problema de estabilidade. Pero traballamos moito para mellorala!</p>
    <p xml:lang="he">ל־Kaidan חסרות כמה יכולות בסיסיות עדיין לצד בעיות יציבות. אבל אנחנו ממש מתאמצים להשתפר!</p>
    <p xml:lang="id">Kaidan belum memiliki semua fitur dasar dan masih memiliki beberapa masalah stabilitas. Namun, kami berusaha sebaik mungkin untuk memperbaikinya!</p>
    <p xml:lang="it">Kaidan non ha ancora tutte le funzionalità di base e ha qualche problema di stabilità, ma stiamo facendo del nostro meglio per migliorarlo.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ka">Kaidan-ს ჯერ არ აქვს ყველა ძირითადი თვისება და ჯერ კიდევ აქვს სტაბილურობის პრობლემები. მაგრამ ჩვენ ყველაფერს ვაკეთებთ მის გასაუმჯობესებლად!</p>
    <p xml:lang="ko">Kaidan에는 아직 빠져 있는 기본 기능이 있으며 완벽히 안정적이지는 않습니다. 최선을 다해서 개선하고 있습니다!</p>
    <p xml:lang="nl">Kaidan heeft no niet alle basisfuncties en er zijn nog steeds enige stabiliteitsproblemen. Maar we doen ons best om het te verbeteren!</p>
    <p xml:lang="pl">Kaidan nadal nie zapewnia wszystkich podstawowych możliwości i ma pewne kłopoty ze stabilnością. Mimo tego robimy wszystko, co możemy, aby zmienić ten stan na lepszy!</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt">O Kaidan ainda não tem todas as funcionalidades básicas, e tem à mesma algumas questões de estabilidade. Mas estamos a dar o nosso melhor para a aperfeiçoar!</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt-BR">O Kaidan ainda não possui todos os recursos básicos e ainda apresenta alguns problemas de estabilidade. Mas estamos fazendo o possível para melhorá-lo!</p>
    <p xml:lang="ru">В Kaidan пока реализованы не все базовые возможности, а также наблюдаются некоторые проблемы со стабильностью. Но разработчики прилагают все усилия для совершенствования программы!</p>
    <p xml:lang="sl">Kaidan še nima vseh osnovnih zmožnosti in ima še vedno nekaj težav s stabilnostjo. A se trudimo po najboljših močeh za izboljšave!</p>
    <p xml:lang="sv">Kaidan har inte alla grundfunktioner ännu och har fortfarande vissa stabilitetsproblem. Men vi gör vårt bästa för att förbättra det!</p>
    <p xml:lang="tr">Kaidan henüz kimi temel özellikleri desteklemez ve kararlılık sorunları olabilir. Ancak onu iyileştirmek için elimizden gelenin en iyisini yapıyoruz!</p>
    <p xml:lang="uk">У Kaidan поки немає усіх базових можливостей і є певні проблеми зі стабільністю. Але ми не припиняємо удосконалювати програму!</p>
    <p xml:lang="zh-CN">Kaidan 尚未具备所有基本功能，仍然存在某些稳定性问题。但我们会尽最大努力改善它！</p>
    <p xml:lang="zh-TW">Kaidan 尚未支援所有基礎功能，並且仍有一些穩定性問題。但我們正努力改善它！</p>
  </description>
  <developer id="org.kde">
    <name>KDE</name>
  </developer>
  <requires>
    <display_length>300</display_length>
  </requires>
  <recommends>
    <control>keyboard</control>
    <control>pointing</control>
    <control>touch</control>
  </recommends>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">im.kaidan.kaidan.desktop</launchable>
  <url type="homepage">https://kaidan.im</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://invent.kde.org/network/kaidan/-/issues</url>
  <url type="help">https://invent.kde.org/network/kaidan/-/wikis/home</url>
  <url type="translate">https://l10n.kde.org/stats/gui/trunk-kf5/package/kaidan/</url>
  <url type="vcs-browser">https://invent.kde.org/network/kaidan</url>
  <categories>
    <category>Network</category>
  </categories>
  <provides>
    <binary>kaidan</binary>
  </provides>
  <translation type="qt">kaidan_qt</translation>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <caption>Chat List and Chat in Landscape Mode</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ar">قائمة الدردشة والدردشة في الوضع الأفقي</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ca">Llista de xats i xat en mode apaïsat</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ca-valencia">Llista de xats i xat en mode apaïsat</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="es">Lista de conversaciones y conversación en modo apaisado</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="eu">Berriketa-zerrenda eta berriketa paisaia moduan</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="fi">Keskusteluluettelo ja keskustelu vaakatilassa</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="fr">Liste de discussions et salon en mode paysage</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="he">רשימת שיחות ושיחה במצב אופקי</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="it">Elenco delle chat e chat in modalità orizzontale</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ka">ჩატების სია და ჩატი ლანდშაფტის რეჟიმში</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ko">가로 모드에서의 채팅 목록과 채팅</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="nl">Chat-lijst en Chat in landschap-modus</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pt-BR">Lista de bate-papo e bate-papo no modo paisagem</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ru">Список чатов и чат в альбомной ориентации</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sl">Seznam klepetov in klepet v ležečem načinu</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sv">Chattlista och chatt i liggande läge</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="tr">Yatay yönelimde sohbet listesi ve sohbet</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="uk">Список спілкування та спілкування в альбомному режимі</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="zh-CN">横屏模式下的聊天列表和聊天</caption>
      <image type="source">https://www.kaidan.im/images/screenshots/screenshot-horizontal.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>Chat in Portrait Mode</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ar">الدردشة في الوضع الرأسي</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ca">Xat en mode retrat</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ca-valencia">Xat en mode retrat</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="es">Conversación en modo retrato</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="eu">Berriketa erretratu moduan</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="fi">Keskustelu pystytilassa</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="fr">Salon en mode portrait</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="he">מצב</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="it">Chat in modalità verticale</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ka">ჩატი პორტრეტის რეჟიმში</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ko">세로 모드에서의 채팅</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="nl">Chat in Portret-modus</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pt-BR">Bate-papo no modo retrato</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ru">Общение в портретном режиме</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sl">Klepet v pokončnem načinu</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sv">Chatt i stående läge</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="tr">Dikey yönelimde sohbet</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="uk">Спілкування у книжковому режимі</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="zh-CN">竖屏模式下的聊天</caption>
      <image type="source">https://www.kaidan.im/images/screenshots/screenshot-vertical.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <releases>
    <release type="stable" version="0.15.0" date="2026-01-30T00:00:00Z">
      <description>
        <p>This release adds the following features:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ar">يضيف هذا الإصدار الميزات التالية:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca">Aquesta versió afegeix les característiques següents:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">Esta versió afig les característiques següents:</p>
        <p xml:lang="pt-BR">Esta versão adiciona as seguintes funcionalidades:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ru">В этом выпуске добавлены следующие возможности:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Add support for audio/video calls (XEP-0166: Jingle, XEP-0167: Jingle RTP Sessions, XEP-0176: Jingle ICE-UDP Transport Method, XEP-0215: External Service Discovery, XEP-0320: Use of DTLS-SRTP in Jingle Sessions, XEP-0353: Jingle Message Initiation) (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إضافة دعم للمكالمات الصوتية والمرئية (XEP-0166: Jingle، وXEP-0167: Jingle RTP Sessions، وXEP-0176: Jingle ICE-UDP Transport Method، وXEP-0215: External Service Discovery، وXEP-0320: Use of DTLS-SRTP in Jingle Sessions، وXEP-0353: Jingle Message Initiation) (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca">Afegeix la implementació de trucades d'àudio/vídeo (XEP-0166: Jingle, XEP-0167: Jingle RTP Sessions, XEP-0176: Jingle ICE-UDP Transport Method, XEP-0215: External Service Discovery, XEP-0320: Ús de DTLS-SRTP a Jingle Sessions, XEP-0353: Jingle Message Initiation) (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">Afig la implementació de tocades d'àudio/vídeo (XEP-0166: Jingle, XEP-0167: Jingle RTP Sessions, XEP-0176: Jingle ICE-UDP Transport Method, XEP-0215: External Service Discovery, XEP-0320: Ús de DTLS-SRTP a Jingle Sessions, XEP-0353: Jingle Message Initiation) (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionado suporte para chamadas de áudio/vídeo (XEP-0166: Jingle, XEP-0167: Sessões RTP Jingle, XEP-0176: Método de transporte ICE-UDP Jingle, XEP-0215: Descoberta de serviço externo, XEP-0320: Uso de DTLS-SRTP em sessões Jingle, XEP-0353: Iniciação de mensagem Jingle) (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ru">Добавлена поддержка аудио- и видеозвонков (XEP-0166: Jingle, XEP-0167: Jingle RTP Sessions, XEP-0176: Jingle ICE-UDP Transport Method, XEP-0215: External Service Discovery, XEP-0320: Use of DTLS-SRTP in Jingle Sessions, XEP-0353: Jingle Message Initiation) (@melvo);</li>
          <li>Show busy indicator while saving captured image/video data (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إظهار مؤشر انشغال أثناء حفظ بيانات الصور/الفيديو الملتقتة (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca">Mostra l'indicador d'ocupat en desar les dades d'imatge/vídeo capturades (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">Mostra l'indicador d'ocupat en guardar les dades d'imatge/vídeo capturades (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Exibir indicador de ocupado enquanto salva os dados de imagem/vídeo capturados (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ru">Отображение индикатора занятости при сохранении снятых изображений или видео;</li>
          <li>Notify on receiving reply to own group chat message if 'On mention' notification setting is enabled (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">التنبيه عند تلقي رد على رسالة دردشة جماعية خاصة إذا فُعّل إعداد التنبيه 'عند الإشارة' (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca">Notifica en rebre resposta al missatge propi de xat del grup si la configuració de notificació «En menció» està activada (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">Notifica en rebre resposta al missatge propi de xat del grup si la configuració de notificació «En menció» està activada (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Notificar ao receber resposta à sua própria mensagem em grupo se a configuração de notificação 'Ao ser mencionado' estiver ativada (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ru">Уведомление о получении ответа на собственное сообщение в групповом чате, если включена настройка уведомлений «При упоминании» (@melvo);</li>
          <li>Select file after opening in folder on Linux if supported (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">تحديد الملف بعد فتحه في المجلد على لينكس إذا كان مدعوماً (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca">Selecciona el fitxer després d'obrir a la carpeta del Linux si s'admet (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">Tria el fitxer després d'obrir a la carpeta de Linux si s'admet (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Selecionar arquivo após abrir na pasta no Linux, se compatível (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ru">Выбор файла после открытия в папке на Linux, если поддерживается (@melvo);</li>
          <li>Improve media capturing look/behavior (including preview after capturing image until image is saved) (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">تحسين مظهر وسلوك التقاط الوسائط (بما في ذلك المعاينة بعد التقاط الصورة حتى تُحفظ) (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca">Millora l'aspecte/comportament de la captura multimèdia (incloent la vista prèvia després de capturar la imatge fins que es desa la imatge) (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">Millora l'aspecte/comportament de la captura multimèdia (incloent la vista prèvia després de capturar la imatge fins que es guarda la imatge) (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Melhoria da aparência/comportamento da captura de mídia (incluindo a pré-visualização após a captura da imagem até que a imagem seja salva) (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ru">Улучшение внешнего вида и поведения захвата медиафайлов (включая предварительный просмотр после захвата изображения до его сохранения) (@melvo);</li>
          <li>Restore focusing of last focused user interface elements (especially message input field) for various use cases (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">استعادة تركيز آخر عناصر واجهة المستخدم التي رُكّز عليها (خاصة حقل إدخال الرسائل) لحالات استخدام متنوعة (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca">Restaura l'enfocament dels últims elements d'interfície d'usuari amb focus (especialment el camp d'entrada de missatges) per a diversos casos d'ús (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">Restaura l'enfocament dels últims elements d'interfície d'usuari amb focus (especialment el camp d'entrada de missatges) per a diversos casos d'ús (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Restaurar o foco nos últimos elementos da interface do usuário que estavam em foco (especialmente o campo de entrada de mensagens) para vários casos de uso (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ru">Восстановление фокуса на последнем элементе интерфейса (особенно поле ввода сообщения) для различных сценариев использования (@melvo);</li>
          <li>Keep message bubble highlighted on reacting/correcting (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إبقاء فقاعة الرسالة مبرزة عند التفاعل أو التصحيح (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca">Manté la bombolla del missatge ressaltada en reaccionar/corregir (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">Manté la bambolla del missatge ressaltada en reaccionar/corregir (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Manter o balão de mensagem destacado ao reagir/corrigir (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ru">Подсвечивать пузырёк сообщения при реакции или исправлении (@melvo);</li>
          <li>Allow to select message for correction via Ctrl+Up/Ctrl+Down (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">السماح بتحديد رسالة للتصحيح عبر اختصارات Ctrl+Up/Ctrl+Down (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca">Permet seleccionar un missatge per a corregir mitjançant Ctrl+Amunt/Ctrl+Avall (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">Permet seleccionar un missatge per a corregir mitjançant «Ctrl+Amunt»/Ctrl+Avall (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Permitir selecionar a mensagem para correção através de Ctrl+Seta para cima/Ctrl+Seta para baixo (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ru">Выбор сообщения для исправления комбинациями клавиш Ctrl+↑/Ctrl+↓ (@melvo);</li>
          <li>Integrate search field into main toolbar increasing space for messages and, on mobile devices, even for chats in chat list (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">دمج حقل البحث في شريط الأدوات الرئيسي لزيادة مساحة الرسائل، وحتى للدردشات في قائمة الدردشة على الأجهزة المحمولة (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca">Integra el camp de cerca a la barra d'eines principal augmentant l'espai per als missatges i, en els dispositius mòbils, fins i tot per als xats a la llista de xats (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">Integra el camp de busca a la barra d'eines principal augmentant l'espai per als missatges i, en els dispositius mòbils, fins i tot per als xats a la llista de xats (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Integrar o campo de pesquisa na barra de ferramentas principal aumentando o espaço para mensagens e, em dispositivos móveis, até mesmo para conversas na lista de bate-papo (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ru">Интеграция поля поиска в главную панель инструментов для увеличения пространства под сообщения, а на мобильных устройствах — даже под чаты в списке чатов (@melvo);</li>
          <li>Show message search field via Ctrl+Shift+F (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إظهار حقل بحث الرسائل عبر اختصار Ctrl+Shift+F (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca">Mostra el camp de cerca de missatges mitjançant Ctrl+Maj+F (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">Mostra el camp de busca de missatges mitjançant «Ctrl+Majús+F» (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Exibir campo de busca de mensagens via Ctrl+Shift+F (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ru">Отображение поля поиска сообщений по комбинации клавиш Ctrl+Shift+F (@melvo);</li>
          <li>Display toolbar buttons on mobile devices exactly as on desktop devices (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">عرض أزرار شريط الأدوات على الأجهزة المحمولة تماماً كما في أجهزة الحاسوب المكتبية (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca">Mostra els botons de la barra d'eines als dispositius mòbils exactament com als dispositius d'escriptori (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">Mostra els botons de la barra d'eines als dispositius mòbils exactament com en els dispositius d'escriptori (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Exibir botões da barra de ferramentas em dispositivos móveis exatamente como em dispositivos desktop (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ru">Отображение кнопок на панели инструментов на мобильных устройствах в точности как на настольных;</li>
          <li>Hide horizontal separator above top-most chat unless chat list is scrolled (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إخفاء الفاصل الأفقي فوق أعلى دردشة ما لم تُمرر قائمة الدردشة (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca">Oculta el separador horitzontal per sobre el xat de la part superior llevat que es desplaci la llista de xats (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">Oculta el separador horitzontal per damunt el xat de la part superior llevat que es desplace la llista de xats (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Ocultar o separador horizontal acima do chat superior, a menos que a lista de chats seja rolada (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ru">Скрыть горизонтальный разделитель над верхним чатом, пока список чатов не прокручен;</li>
          <li>Store passwords in unencrypted file if no password manager is available or corresponding command-line option provided (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">تخزين كلمات السر في ملف غير معمي إذا لم يتوفر مدير كلمات سر أو إذا وُفر خيار سطر الأوامر المقابل (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca">Emmagatzema les contrasenyes en un fitxer sense encriptar si no hi ha cap gestor de contrasenyes disponible o es proporciona l'opció corresponent de la línia d'ordres (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">Emmagatzema les contrasenyes en un fitxer sense encriptar si no hi ha cap gestor de contrasenyes disponible o es proporciona l'opció corresponent de la línia d'ordres (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Armazenar as senhas em um arquivo não criptografado se nenhum gerenciador de senhas estiver disponível ou se a opção de linha de comando correspondente não for fornecida (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ru">Сохранение паролей в незашифрованном файле, если менеджер паролей недоступен или указана соответствующая опция командной строки (@fazevedo);</li>
          <li>Migrate unencrypted passwords to password manager if available on start (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">نقل كلمات السر غير المعمية إلى مدير كلمات السر عند البدء إذا كان متاحاً (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca">Migra les contrasenyes sense encriptar al gestor de contrasenyes si està disponible a l'inici (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">Migra les contrasenyes sense encriptar al gestor de contrasenyes si està disponible a l'inici (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Migração das senhas não criptografadas para um gerenciador de senhas, se disponível, na inicialização (@fazevedo)</li>
        </ul>
        <p>This release fixes the following bugs:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ar">يصلح هذا الإصدار العلل التالية:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca">Aquesta versió soluciona els errors següents:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">Esta versió soluciona els errors següents:</p>
        <p xml:lang="pt-BR">Esta versão corrige os seguintes bugs:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fix overlapping message bubble tail (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح تداخل ذيل فقاعة الرسالة (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca">Corregeix la cua de les bombolles de missatges que se superposen (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">Corregix la cua de les bambolles de missatge que se superposen (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção da sobreposição na cauda do balão de mensagem (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix medium preview hovering if hidden drop area info is hovered (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح حومان معاينة الوسائط إذا حُوّم فوق معلومات منطقة الإفلات المخفية (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca">Corregeix la vista prèvia del mitjà en passar per sobre si es passa per sobre de la informació de l'àrea oculta de deixar anar (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">Corregix la vista prèvia del mitjà en passar per damunt si es passa per damunt de la informació de l'àrea oculta de deixar anar (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Corrigido o problema de pré-visualização de tamanho médio ao passar o cursor sobre informações ocultas da área de destino (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix updating OMEMO 2 keys for all use cases (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح تحديث مفاتيح OMEMO 2 لجميع حالات الاستخدام (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca">Corregeix l'actualització de les claus OMEMO 2 per a tots els casos d'ús (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">Corregix l'actualització de les claus OMEMO 2 per a tots els casos d'ús (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Corrigido o problema de atualização das chaves OMEMO 2 para todos os casos de uso (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix deadlock on logout during upload of multiple files (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح حالة الجمود عند الخروج أثناء رفع ملفات متعددة (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca">Corregeix un bloqueig en tancar la sessió durant la pujada de diversos fitxers (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">Corregix un bloqueig en tancar la sessió durant la pujada de diversos fitxers (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção do deadlock no logout durante o upload de vários arquivos (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix creating additional database connection on wrong thread (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح إنشاء اتصال قاعدة بيانات إضافي على خيط خاطئ (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca">Corregeix la creació de connexió de base de dades addicional en un fil incorrecte (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">Corregix la creació de connexió de base de dades addicional en un fil incorrecte (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção da criação de uma conexão de banco de dados adicional na thread errada (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix sending/resetting whether message is being composed for various corner cases (switching chat, logging out, disabling corresponding setting) (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح إرسال/إعادة ضبط حالة كتابة الرسالة لحالات متنوعة (تبديل الدردشة، الخروج، تعطيل الإعداد المقابل) (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca">Corregeix l'enviament/reinicialització si el missatge s'està redactant per a diversos casos extrems (canviar de xat, tancar la sessió, desactivar la configuració corresponent) (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">Corregix l'enviament/reinicialització si el missatge s'està redactant per a diversos casos extrems (canviar de xat, tancar la sessió, desactivar la configuració corresponent) (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção do envio/redefinição do status da composição da mensagem para vários casos extremos (alternar entre chats, sair da sessão, desativar a configuração correspondente) (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix updating last message on receiving initial message after setting up existing account in Kaidan for first time (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح تحديث آخر رسالة عند تلقي الرسالة الأولية بعد إعداد حساب موجود في كيدان لأول مرة (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca">Corregeix l'actualització del darrer missatge en rebre el missatge inicial després de configurar el compte existent al Kaidan per primera vegada (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">Corregix l'actualització de l'últim missatge en rebre el missatge inicial després de configurar el compte existent a Kaidan per primera vegada (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção da atualização da última mensagem ao receber a mensagem inicial após configurar uma conta existente no Kaidan pela primeira vez (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix resetting draft message after canceling message correction (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح إعادة ضبط مسودة الرسالة بعد إلغاء تصحيح الرسالة (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca">Corregeix el restabliment de l'esborrany de missatge després de cancel·lar la correcció del missatge (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">Corregix el restabliment de l'esborrany de missatge després de cancel·lar la correcció del missatge (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Corrigido o problema de redefinição da mensagem de rascunho após o cancelamento da correção da mensagem (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix resending failed message reaction (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح إعادة إرسال تفاعل الرسالة الفاشل (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca">Corregeix el reenviament de la reacció de missatge que ha fallat (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">Corregix el reenviament de la reacció de missatge que ha fallat (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção da reação ao reenvio de mensagens com falha (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix selecting previously selected message after changing reactions (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح تحديد الرسالة المحددة سابقاً بعد تغيير التفاعلات (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca">Corregeix la selecció del missatge seleccionat prèviament després de canviar les reaccions (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">Corregix la selecció del missatge seleccionat prèviament després de canviar les reaccions (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção do problema ao selecionar a mensagem previamente selecionada após alterar as reações (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix restoring message highlighting and cancel ongoing correction/reply on removing corresponding message (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح استعادة إبراز الرسالة وإلغاء التصحيح/الرد الجاري عند إزالة الرسالة المقابلة (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca">Corregeix la restauració del ressaltat del missatge i cancel·la la correcció/resposta en curs en eliminar el missatge corresponent (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">Corregix la restauració del ressaltat del missatge i cancel·la la correcció/resposta en curs en eliminar el missatge corresponent (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Corrigido o problema que restaura o destaque de mensagens e cancela a correção/resposta em andamento ao remover a mensagem correspondente (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix displaying last message sender in chat list after draft message removal (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح عرض مرسل آخر رسالة في قائمة الدردشة بعد إزالة مسودة الرسالة (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca">Corregeix la visualització del remitent de l'últim missatge a la llista de xats després de l'eliminació d'esborranys de missatges (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">Corregix la visualització del remitent de l'últim missatge a la llista de xats després de l'eliminació d'esborranys de missatges (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Corrigido o problema que impedia a exibição do último remetente da mensagem na lista de bate-papo após a remoção de uma mensagem em rascunho (@melvo)</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Kaidan requires Kirigami Addons 1.8 now</p>
        <p xml:lang="ar">يتطلب كيدان الآن ملحقات Kirigami الإصدار 1.8</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca">El Kaidan requereix ara els Kirigami Addons 1.8</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">Kaidan requerix ara Kirigami Addons 1.8</p>
        <p xml:lang="pt-BR">O Kaidan agora requer Kirigami Addons 1.8</p>
        <p>Kaidan requires QXmpp 1.14 now</p>
        <p xml:lang="ar">يتطلب كيدان الآن مكتبة QXmpp الإصدار 1.14</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca">El Kaidan requereix ara QXmpp 1.14</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">Kaidan requerix ara QXmpp 1.14</p>
        <p xml:lang="pt-BR">O Kaidan agora requer QXmpp 1.14</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release type="stable" version="0.14.0" date="2026-01-01T00:00:00Z">
      <description>
        <p>This release adds the following features:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ar">يضيف هذا الإصدار الميزات التالية:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca">Aquesta versió afegeix les característiques següents:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">Esta versió afig les característiques següents:</p>
        <p xml:lang="pt-BR">Esta versão adiciona as seguintes funcionalidades:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ru">В этом выпуске добавлены следующие возможности:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Keep draft messages on top of pinned/unpinned chat list items (@pehg)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إبقاء مسودات الرسائل في أعلى عناصر قائمة الدردشة المثبتة وغير المثبتة (@pehg)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca">Manté els esborranys de missatges a sobre dels elements fixats/no fixats de la llista de xats (@pehg)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">Manté els esborranys de missatges damunt dels elements fixats/no fixats de la llista de xats (@pehg)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Manter as mensagens em rascunho no topo dos itens fixados/não fixados da lista de bate-papo (@pehg)</li>
          <li>Optimize thumbnail creation (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">تحسين إنشاء المصغرات (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca">Optimitza la creació de miniatures (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">Optimitza la creació de miniatures (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Otimização da criação de miniaturas (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li>Display border around searched/referenced message instead of bar (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">عرض إطار حول الرسالة المبحوث عنها أو المشار إليها بدلاً من الشريط (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca">Mostra la vora al voltant del missatge cercat/referenciat en lloc de la barra (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">Mostra la vora al voltant del missatge buscat/referenciat en lloc de la barra (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Exibir borda ao redor da mensagem pesquisada/referenciada em vez de barra (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Display border around message if its context menu is shown (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">عرض إطار حول الرسالة إذا كانت قائمتها السياقية معروضة (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca">Mostra la vora al voltant del missatge si es mostra el seu menú contextual (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">Mostra la vora al voltant del missatge si es mostra el seu menú contextual (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Exibir borda ao redor da mensagem se o menu de contexto dela estiver visível (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Highlight message's avatar if hovered (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إبراز الصورة الرمزية للرسالة عند الحومان فوقها (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca">Ressalta l'avatar del missatge si es passa per sobre (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">Ressalta l'avatar del missatge si es passa per damunt (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Destacar o avatar da mensagem ao passar o cursor sobre ela (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Display provider chat (used for welcome messages and service announcements) as such (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">عرض دردشة المزود (المستخدمة لرسائل الترحيب وإعلانات الخدمة) بصفتها تلك (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca">Mostra el xat del proveïdor (utilitzat per a missatges de benvinguda i anuncis de servei) com a tal (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">Mostra el xat del proveïdor (utilitzat per a missatges de benvinguda i anuncis de servei) com a tal (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Exibir o chat do provedor (usado para mensagens de boas-vindas e anúncios de serviço) como tal (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Always display same name and proper avatar initials for notes chats (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">عرض نفس الاسم والأحرف الأولى المناسبة للصورة الرمزية دائماً لدردشات الملاحظات (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca">Mostra sempre el mateix nom i les inicials d'avatar adequades per als xats de notes (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">Mostra sempre el mateix nom i les inicials d'avatar adequades per als xats de notes (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Sempre exibir o mesmo nome e as iniciais corretas do avatar nas conversas de notas (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Allow to cancel downloads/uploads (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">السماح بإلغاء التنزيلات والرفوعات (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca">Permet cancel·lar baixades/pujades (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">Permet cancel·lar baixades/pujades (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Permitir cancelamento de downloads/uploads (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li>Allow to restart canceled uploads (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">السماح بإعادة تشغيل الرفوعات الملغاة (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca">Permet reiniciar les pujades cancel·lades (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">Permet reiniciar les pujades cancel·lades (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Permitir reiniciar uploads cancelados (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li>Allow to resend failed message via context menu (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">السماح بإعادة إرسال الرسالة الفاشلة عبر القائمة السياقية (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca">Permet reenviar un missatge que ha fallat a través del menú contextual (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">Permet reenviar un missatge que ha fallat a través del menú contextual (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Permitir reenviar mensagens com falha através do menu de contexto (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Retrieve support addresses from server instead of provider list (XEP-0157: Contact Addresses for XMPP Services, XEP-0128: Service Discovery Extensions) (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">جلب عناوين الدعم من الخادوم بدلاً من قائمة المزودين (XEP-0157: Contact Addresses for XMPP Services، وXEP-0128: Service Discovery Extensions) (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca">Recupera les adreces de suport del servidor en lloc de la llista de proveïdors (XEP-0157: Adreces de contacte per als serveis XMPP, XEP-0128: Extensions de descobriment de serveis) (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">Recupera les adreces de suport del servidor en lloc de la llista de proveïdors (XEP-0157: Adreces de contacte per als serveis XMPP, XEP-0128: Extensions de descobriment de serveis) (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Recuperar endereços de suporte do servidor em vez da lista de provedores (XEP-0157: Endereços de contato para serviços XMPP, XEP-0128: Extensões de descoberta de serviços) (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Allow adding contact by entering XMPP URI (including authentication of OMEMO 2 keys) (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">السماح بإضافة جهة اتصال عبر إدخال رابط XMPP URI (بما في ذلك استيثاق مفاتيح OMEMO 2) (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca">Permet afegir un contacte introduint un URI de XMPP (inclosa l'autenticació de les claus OMEMO 2) (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">Permet afegir un contacte introduint un URI de XMPP (inclosa l'autenticació de les claus OMEMO 2) (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Permitir a adição de contatos através da inserção do URI XMPP (incluindo a autenticação das chaves OMEMO 2) (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Allow joining group chat by entering XMPP URI (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">السماح بالانضمام إلى دردشة جماعية عبر إدخال رابط XMPP URI (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca">Permet unir-se al xat de grup introduint un URI de XMPP (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">Permet unir-se al xat de grup introduint un URI de XMPP (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Permitir a entrada em bate-papo em grupo inserindo o URI XMPP (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Add option for allowing SASL PLAIN (needed for servers using LDAP) to custom connection settings (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إضافة خيار للسماح بـ SASL PLAIN (مطلوب للخواديم التي تستخدم LDAP) إلى إعدادات الاتصال المخصصة (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca">Afegeix una opció per permetre SASL PLAIN (cal per als servidors que utilitzen LDAP) a la configuració de connexió personalitzada (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">Afig una opció per permetre SASL PLAIN (cal per als servidors que utilitzen LDAP) a la configuració de connexió personalitzada (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionada opção para permitir SASL PLAIN (necessário para servidores que usam LDAP) nas configurações de conexão personalizadas (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Add filtering options to choose provider for registration (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إضافة خيارات تصفية لاختيار مزود للتسجيل (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca">Afegeix opcions de filtratge per a triar un proveïdor per a registrar-se (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">Afig opcions de filtratge per a triar un proveïdor per a registrar-se (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionadas opções de filtro para escolher o provedor de registro (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Cancel file transfers on disconnecting from server (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إلغاء نقل الملفات عند قطع الاتصال بالخادوم (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca">Cancel·la les transferències de fitxers en desconnectar-se del servidor (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">Cancel·la les transferències de fitxers en desconnectar-se del servidor (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Cancelar transferências de arquivos ao desconectar do servidor (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li>Add support for offline media sharing queue (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إضافة دعم لرتل مشاركة الوسائط دون اتصال (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca">Afegeix la implementació per a la cua de compartició multimèdia fora de línia (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">Afig la implementació per a la cua de compartició multimèdia fora de línia (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionado suporte para fila de compartilhamento de mídia offline (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li>Restart downloads canceled on logout once logged in (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إعادة تشغيل التنزيلات الملغاة عند الخروج بمجرد الولوج ثانية (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca">Reinicia les baixades cancel·lades en tancar la sessió un cop iniciada la sessió (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">Reinicia les baixades cancel·lades en tancar la sessió una vegada iniciada la sessió (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Reiniciar downloads cancelados ao sair da sessão após o login (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Remove all related data on message removal (such as reactions and media) (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إزالة جميع البيانات المرتبطة عند إزالة الرسالة (مثل التفاعلات والوسائط) (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Remover todos os dados relacionados à remoção da mensagem (como reações e mídia) (@melvo)</li>
        </ul>
        <p>This release fixes the following bugs:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ar">يصلح هذا الإصدار العلل التالية:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca">Aquesta versió soluciona els errors següents:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">Esta versió soluciona els errors següents:</p>
        <p xml:lang="pt-BR">Esta versão corrige os seguintes bugs:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fix displaying message reaction details (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح عرض تفاصيل تفاعل الرسالة (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção da exibição dos detalhes da reação da mensagem (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix adding unneeded separator on mention after new line (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح إضافة فاصل غير ضروري عند الإشارة بعد سطر جديد (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção do separador desnecessário adicionado à menção após a nova linha (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Wrap hint for actions needing user to be connected to server (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">لف التلميح للإجراءات التي تتطلب اتصال المستخدم بالخادوم (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Dica de encapsulamento para ações que exigem que o usuário esteja conectado ao servidor (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix displaying icons on Windows (@pehg)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح عرض الأيقونات على ويندوز (@pehg)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção do problema de exibição de ícones no Windows (@pehg)</li>
          <li>Fix adding new line at cursor position (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح إضافة سطر جديد عند موضع المؤشر (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção da adição de nova linha na posição do cursor (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Ensure that own encryption devices are not removed if notes chat is removed (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">التأكد من عدم إزالة أجهزة التعمية الخاصة إذا أُزيلت دردشة الملاحظات (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Certifica-se de que seus dispositivos de criptografia não sejam removidos caso o chat de notas seja removido (@melvo)</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Kaidan requires KIconThemes (for Windows) now</p>
        <p xml:lang="ar">يتطلب كيدان الآن سمات الأيقونات KIconThemes (لويندوز)</p>
        <p xml:lang="pt-BR">O Kaidan agora requer KIconThemes (para Windows)</p>
        <p>Kaidan requires Qt6GuiPrivate (for Qt 6.10 or above) now</p>
        <p xml:lang="ar">يتطلب كيدان الآن مكتبة Qt6GuiPrivate (لـ Qt 6.10 فما فوق)</p>
        <p xml:lang="pt-BR">O Kaidan agora requer Qt6GuiPrivate (para Qt 6.10 ou superior)</p>
        <p>Kaidan requires Qt 6.7 now</p>
        <p xml:lang="ar">يتطلب كيدان الآن Qt 6.7</p>
        <p xml:lang="pt-BR">O Kaidan agora requer o Qt 6.7</p>
        <p>Kaidan requires QXmpp 1.13 now</p>
        <p xml:lang="ar">يتطلب كيدان الآن QXmpp 1.13</p>
        <p xml:lang="pt-BR">O Kaidan agora requer QXmpp 1.13</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release type="stable" version="0.13.0" date="2025-09-21T00:00:00Z">
      <description>
        <p>This release adds the following features:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ar">يضيف هذا الإصدار الميزات التالية:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca">Aquesta versió afegeix les característiques següents:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">Esta versió afig les característiques següents:</p>
        <p xml:lang="pt-BR">Esta versão adiciona as seguintes funcionalidades:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ru">В этом выпуске добавлены следующие возможности:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Add support for using multiple accounts simultaneously (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إضافة دعم لاستخدام حسابات متعددة في وقت واحد (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionado suporte para usar várias contas simultaneamente (@melvo)</li>
          <li>List accounts and show button to add new accounts (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">سرد الحسابات وإظهار زر لإضافة حسابات جديدة (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Listar contas e mostrar botão para adicionar novas contas (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Show dialog to select account for global action such as adding a contact (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إظهار حوار لاختيار الحساب للإجراءات العامة مثل إضافة جهة اتصال (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Exibir caixa de diálogo para selecionar a conta para ação global, como a adição de um contato (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Allow to enable/disable accounts instead of connecting/disconnecting them manually (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">السماح بتفعيل/تعطيل الحسابات بدلاً من وصلها/فصلها يدوياً (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Permitir ativar/desativar contas em vez de conectá-las/desconectá-las manualmente (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Update nicknames of own accounts once connected (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">تحديث ألقاب الحسابات الخاصة بمجرد الاتصال (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Atualização dos apelidos das suas próprias contas assim que estiver conectado (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Show small account avatars next to regular avatars if multiple accounts are used (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إظهار صور رمزية صغيرة للحسابات بجانب الصور الرمزية العادية عند استخدام حسابات متعددة (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Exibir avatares de conta pequenos ao lado dos avatares normais se várias contas forem usadas (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Hide global drawer handle on chat if window is narrow (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إخفاء مقبض الدرج العالمي في الدردشة إذا كانت النافذة ضيقة (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Ocultar a alça global do menu de bate-papo se a janela for estreita (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Use PNG/.png instead of JPEG/.jpg for thumbnails to allow transparency (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">استخدام PNG/.png بدلاً من JPEG/.jpg للمصغرات للسماح بالشفافية (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Usar PNG/.png em vez de JPEG/.jpg para miniaturas para permitir transparência (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Use AAC/.m4a instead of MP3/.mp3 for voice messages to improve compatibility (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">استخدام AAC/.m4a بدلاً من MP3/.mp3 للرسائل الصوتية لتحسين التوافق (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Usar AAC/.m4a em vez de MP3/.mp3 para mensagens de voz para melhorar a compatibilidade (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Provide size of sent images to recipients allowing receiving client to scale thumbnails to size of original image (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">توفير حجم الصور المرسلة للمستلمين بما يسمح للعميل المستلم بتغيير حجم المصغرات لتناسب حجم الصورة الأصلية (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Fornecer o tamanho das imagens enviadas aos destinatários, permitindo que o cliente receptor redimensione as miniaturas para o tamanho da imagem original (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Provide size of generated thumbnails to recipients (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">توفير حجم المصغرات المولدة للمستلمين (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Fornecer o tamanho das miniaturas geradas aos destinatários (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Increase size of generated thumbnails (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">زيادة حجم المصغرات المولدة (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Aumentar o tamanho das miniaturas geradas (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Show circle instead of bar for upload/download progress (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إظهار دائرة بدلاً من شريط لتقدم الرفع/التنزيل (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Exibir círculo em vez de barra para o progresso de upload/download (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Try all providers on connection error during automatic registration (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">تجربة جميع المزودين عند حدوث خطأ في الاتصال أثناء التسجيل الآلي (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Tentar todos os provedores em caso de erro de conexão durante o registro automático (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Add message forwarding (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إضافة إعادة توجيه الرسائل (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionado o encaminhamento de mensagens (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Enable voice message recording via Flatpak (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">تفعيل تسجيل الرسائل الصوتية عبر Flatpak (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Ativada a gravação de mensagens de voz via Flatpak (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Store account passwords encrypted if password manager is available (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">تخزين كلمات سر الحسابات معمية إذا كان مدير كلمات السر متاحاً (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Armazenar as senhas das contas criptografadas se um gerenciador de senhas estiver disponível (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li>Apply consistent criteria for all message corrections (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">تطبيق معايير متسقة لجميع تصحيحات الرسائل (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Aplicar critérios consistentes para todas as correções de mensagens (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Add support to mark messages locally in order to reply to them later or to quickly find important messages (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إضافة دعم لوسم الرسائل محلياً من أجل الرد عليها لاحقاً أو العثور على الرسائل الهامة بسرعة (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionado suporte para marcar mensagens localmente para respondê-las mais tarde ou para encontrar rapidamente mensagens importantes (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Reuse SASL 2 user agent and FAST token on every restart for faster connection establishment (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إعادة استخدام وكيل مستخدم SASL 2 ووسم FAST في كل عملية إعادة تشغيل لإنشاء اتصال أسرع (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Reutilizar o agente de usuário SASL 2 e o token FAST a cada reinicialização para um estabelecimento de conexão mais rápido (@melvo)</li>
        </ul>
        <p>This release fixes the following bugs:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ar">يصلح هذا الإصدار العلل التالية:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca">Aquesta versió soluciona els errors següents:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">Esta versió soluciona els errors següents:</p>
        <p xml:lang="pt-BR">Esta versão corrige os seguintes bugs:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fix selecting media via long press in media overview (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح تحديد الوسائط عبر الضغط المطول في نظرة الوسائط العامة (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção da seleção de mídia por meio de um toque longo na visão geral de mídia (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix OMEMO initialization (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح تهيئة OMEMO (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção da inicialização do OMEMO (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix displaying geo location map (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح عرض خريطة الموقع الجغرافي (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção do problema na exibição do mapa de geolocalização (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix showing hints on invalid input of various input fields (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح إظهار التلميحات عند وجود مدخلات غير صالحة في حقول الإدخال المختلفة (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção na exibição de dicas sobre entradas inválidas em vários campos de entrada (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix name/date of chat list item moving if counter for unread messages dis-/appears (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح تحرك اسم/تاريخ عنصر قائمة الدردشة عند ظهور/اختفاء عداد الرسائل غير المقروءة (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção da movimentação do nome/data do item da lista de bate-papo caso o contador de mensagens não lidas desapareça/apareça (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix counter for unread messages (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح عداد الرسائل غير المقروءة (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção do contador de mensagens não lidas (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix handling removed message reactions (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح معالجة تفاعلات الرسائل المزالة (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção do tratamento de reações a mensagens removidas (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix canceling personal data sharing via contact details (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح إلغاء مشاركة البيانات الشخصية عبر تفاصيل جهة الاتصال (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção do cancelamento do compartilhamento de dados pessoais por meio de informações de contato (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix finding existing notifications for personal data sharing requests (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح العثور على التنبيهات الموجودة لطلبات مشاركة البيانات الشخصية (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção do problema na localização de notificações existentes para solicitações de compartilhamento de dados pessoais (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix cursor behavior in message input field by allowing vertical cursor movements while participant picker is closed and prohibiting horizontal cursor movements while participant picker is open (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح سلوك المؤشر في حقل إدخال الرسالة عبر السماح بحركات المؤشر الرأسية أثناء إغلاق منتقي المشاركين ومنع حركات المؤشر الأفقية أثناء فتحه (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção do comportamento do cursor no campo de entrada de mensagens, permitindo movimentos verticais do cursor enquanto o seletor de participantes estiver fechado e proibindo movimentos horizontais do cursor enquanto o seletor de participantes estiver aberto (@melvo)</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Kaidan requires QtKeychain 0.15 now</p>
        <p xml:lang="ar">يتطلب كيدان الآن QtKeychain 0.15</p>
        <p xml:lang="pt-BR">O Kaidan agora requer o QtKeychain 0.15</p>
        <p>Kaidan requires QXmpp 1.11 now</p>
        <p xml:lang="ar">يتطلب كيدان الآن QXmpp 1.11</p>
        <p xml:lang="pt-BR">O Kaidan agora requer QXmpp 1.11</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release type="stable" version="0.12.2" date="2025-03-30T00:00:00Z">
      <description>
        <p>This release fixes the following bugs:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ar">يصلح هذا الإصدار العلل التالية:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca">Aquesta versió soluciona els errors següents:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">Esta versió soluciona els errors següents:</p>
        <p xml:lang="pt-BR">Esta versão corrige os seguintes bugs:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fix removing corrected message (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح إزالة الرسالة المصححة (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Corrigido o problema da remoção da mensagem corrigida (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix showing message bubble tail only for first message of sender (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح إظهار ذيل فقاعة الرسالة للرسالة الأولى من المرسل فقط (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Corrigido o problema que mostrava a cauda do balão de mensagem apenas na primeira mensagem do remetente (@melvo)</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release type="stable" version="0.12.1" date="2025-03-29T00:00:00Z">
      <description>
        <p>This release fixes the following bugs:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ar">يصلح هذا الإصدار العلل التالية:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca">Aquesta versió soluciona els errors següents:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">Esta versió soluciona els errors següents:</p>
        <p xml:lang="pt-BR">Esta versão corrige os seguintes bugs:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Do not highlight unpinned chats when pinned chat is moved (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">عدم إبراز الدردشات غير المثبتة عند نقل دردشة مثبتة (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Não destacar conversas não fixadas quando a conversa fixada for movida (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix deleting/sending voice messages (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح حذف أو إرسال الرسائل الصوتية (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção do problema ao apagar/enviar mensagens de voz (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix crash during login (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح الانهيار أثناء الولوج (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção da falha durante o login (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix opening chat again after going back to chat list on narrow window (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح فتح الدردشة مرة أخرى بعد العودة لقائمة الدردشة في النافذة الضيقة (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção do problema ao abrir o chat novamente após retornar à lista de chats em janelas estreitas (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Increase toolbar height to fix avatar not being recognizable (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">زيادة ارتفاع شريط الأدوات لإصلاح عدم إمكانية تمييز الصورة الرمزية (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Aumenta a altura da barra de ferramentas para corrigir o problema do avatar não ser reconhecido (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix width of search bar above chat list to take available space while showing all buttons (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح عرض شريط البحث فوق قائمة الدردشة ليشغل المساحة المتاحة مع إظهار جميع الأزرار (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Ajusta a largura da barra de pesquisa acima da lista de bate-papo para aproveitar o espaço disponível enquanto mostrando todos os botões (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix storing changed password (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح تخزين كلمة السر المغيرة (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Corrigido o armazenamento de senha alterada (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix setting custom host/port for account registration (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح ضبط المضيف/المنفذ المخصص لتسجيل الحساب (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção da configuração de host/porta personalizados para registro de conta (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix crash on chat removal (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح الانهيار عند إزالة الدردشة (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Corrigido o problema que causava o fechamento inesperado do chat (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li>Move device switching options into account details to fix long credentials not being shown and login QR code being temporarily visible on opening dialog (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">نقل خيارات تبديل الجهاز إلى تفاصيل الحساب لإصلاح عدم عرض بيانات الاعتماد الطويلة وظهور رمز الاستجابة السريعة للولوج مؤقتاً عند فتح الحوار (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Move as opções de troca de dispositivo para os detalhes da conta para corrigir o problema de credenciais longas não serem exibidas e o código QR de login ficar temporariamente visível na caixa de diálogo de abertura (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Allow setting new password on error to fix not being able to log in after changing password via other device (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">السماح بضبط كلمة سر جديدة عند حدوث خطأ لإصلاح عدم القدرة على الولوج بعد تغيير كلمة السر عبر جهاز آخر (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Permitir a definição de uma nova senha em caso de erro para corrigir o problema de não conseguir iniciar sessão após a alteração da senha através de outro dispositivo (@melvo)</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release type="stable" version="0.12.0" date="2025-03-21T00:00:00Z">
      <description>
        <p>This release adds the following features:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ar">يضيف هذا الإصدار الميزات التالية:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca">Aquesta versió afegeix les característiques següents:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">Esta versió afig les característiques següents:</p>
        <p xml:lang="pt-BR">Esta versão adiciona as seguintes funcionalidades:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ru">В этом выпуске добавлены следующие возможности:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Use square selection to crop avatars (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">استخدام تحديد مربع لقص الصور الرمزية (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Usar a seleção quadrada para recortar avatares (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li>Use background with rounded corners for chat list items (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">استخدام خلفية بزوايا مدورة لعناصر قائمة الدردشة (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Usar um fundo com cantos arredondados para os itens da lista de bate-papo (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Remove colored availability indicator from chat list item (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إزالة مؤشر التوافر الملون من عنصر قائمة الدردشة (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Remove indicador de disponibilidade colorido do item da lista de bate-papo (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Display group chat participant picker above text cursor in large windows (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">عرض منتقي مشاركي الدردشة الجماعية فوق مؤشر النص في النوافذ الكبيرة (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Exibir seletor de participantes do bate-papo em grupo acima do cursor de texto em janelas grandes (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Do not allow to enter/send messages without visible characters (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">عدم السماح بإدخال أو إرسال رسائل دون محارف مرئية (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Não permitir a entrada/envio de mensagens sem caracteres visíveis (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Remove leading/trailing whitespace from exchanged messages (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إزالة الفراغات البيضاء البادئة واللاحقة من الرسائل المتبادلة (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Remove espaços em branco iniciais/finais das mensagens trocadas (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Ignore received messages without displayable content if they cannot be otherwise processed (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">تجاهل الرسائل المستلمة التي ليس لها محتوى قابل للعرض إذا تعذرت معالجتها بطريقة أخرى (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Ignorar as mensagens recebidas sem conteúdo exibível se elas não puderem ser processadas de outra forma (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Allow to show/hide buttons to pin/move chat list items (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">السماح بإظهار/إخفاء أزرار تثبيت أو نقل عناصر قائمة الدردشة (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Permitir mostrar/ocultar botões para fixar/mover itens da lista de bate-papo (@melvo)</li>
        </ul>
        <p>This release fixes the following bugs:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ar">يصلح هذا الإصدار العلل التالية:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca">Aquesta versió soluciona els errors següents:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">Esta versió soluciona els errors següents:</p>
        <p xml:lang="pt-BR">Esta versão corrige os seguintes bugs:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fix style for Flatpak (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح النمط لـ Flatpak (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção do estilo para Flatpak (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix displaying video thumbnails and opening files for Flatpak (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح عرض مصغرات الفيديو وفتح الملفات لـ Flatpak (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção na exibição de miniaturas de vídeo e na abertura de arquivos Flatpak (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix message reaction details not opening a second time (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح عدم فتح تفاصيل تفاعل الرسالة للمرة الثانية (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção do problema em que os detalhes da reação à mensagem não abrem uma segunda vez (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix opening contact addition view on receiving XMPP URIs (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح فتح عرض إضافة جهة الاتصال عند تلقي روابط XMPP URI (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção da visualização de adição de contato ao receber URIs XMPP (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix format of text following emojis (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح تنسيق النص التابع للرموز التعبيرية (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção da formatação do texto após emojis (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix eliding last message text for chat list item (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح قص نص آخر رسالة لعنصر قائمة الدردشة (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção da omissão do texto da última mensagem para o item da lista de bate-papo (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix unit tests (@mlaurent, @fazevedo, @melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح اختبارات الوحدة (@mlaurent, @fazevedo, @melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção dos testes de unidade (@mlaurent, @fazevedo, @melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix storing downloaded files with unique names (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح تخزين الملفات المنزلة بأسماء فريدة (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção do armazenamento de arquivos baixados com nomes exclusivos (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix overlay to change/open avatars shown before hovered in account/contact details (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح الطبقة المتراكبة لتغيير/فتح الصور الرمزية المعروضة قبل الحومان في تفاصيل الحساب/جهة الاتصال (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção da sobreposição para alterar/abrir avatares exibidos antes de passar o cursor sobre os detalhes da conta/contato (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix verification of moved contacts (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح التحقق من جهات الاتصال المنقولة (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção da verificação de contatos movidos (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li>Fix setting up end-to-end encryption (OMEMO 2) after account migration (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح إعداد التعمية بين الطرفين (OMEMO 2) بعد نقل الحساب (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção do problema na configuração da criptografia de ponta a ponta (OMEMO 2) após a migração de conta (@melvo)</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Kaidan requires KWindowSystem and KDSingleApplication now (@mlaurent)</p>
        <p xml:lang="ar">يتطلب كيدان الآن KWindowSystem و KDSingleApplication (@mlaurent)</p>
        <p xml:lang="pt-BR">O Kaidan agora requer KWindowSystem e KDSingleApplication (@mlaurent)</p>
        <p>Kaidan requires KDE Frameworks 6.11 now</p>
        <p xml:lang="ar">يتطلب كيدان الآن أطر عمل كدي 6.11</p>
        <p xml:lang="pt-BR">O Kaidan agora requer o KDE Frameworks 6.11</p>
        <p>Kaidan requires KQuickImageEditor 0.5 now</p>
        <p xml:lang="ar">يتطلب كيدان الآن KQuickImageEditor 0.5</p>
        <p xml:lang="pt-BR">O Kaidan agora requer o KQuickImageEditor 0.5</p>
        <p>Kaidan requires QXmpp 1.10.3 now</p>
        <p xml:lang="ar">يتطلب كيدان الآن QXmpp 1.10.3</p>
        <p xml:lang="pt-BR">O Kaidan agora requer QXmpp 1.10.3</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release type="stable" version="0.11.0" date="2025-02-14T00:00:00Z">
      <description>
        <p>This release adds the following features:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ar">يضيف هذا الإصدار الميزات التالية:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca">Aquesta versió afegeix les característiques següents:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">Esta versió afig les característiques següents:</p>
        <p xml:lang="pt-BR">Esta versão adiciona as seguintes funcionalidades:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ru">В этом выпуске добавлены следующие возможности:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Highlight public XMPP provider titles while card is expanded (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إبراز عناوين مزودي XMPP العامين أثناء توسيع البطاقة (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Destacar os títulos de provedores XMPP públicos enquanto o cartão estiver expandido (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Round corners of cards and buttons (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">تدوير زوايا البطاقات والأزرار (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Cantos arredondados de cartões e botões (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Add fading in/out hover effect to map previews (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إضافة تأثير حومان بالتلاشي للداخل/للخارج لمعاينات الخرائط (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adiciona efeito de transição gradual ao passar o mouse sobre as pré-visualizações do mapa (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Collapse contact profiles by default if they have more than 3 entries (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">طي تشكيلات جهات الاتصال مبدئياً إذا كانت تحتوي على أكثر من 3 مدخلات (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Ocultar perfis de contato por padrão se eles tiverem mais de 3 entradas (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Show colored check mark for delivered messages instead of none to avoid message bubble resizing (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إظهار علامة اختيار ملونة للرسائل المسلمة بدلاً من لا شيء لتجنب تغيير حجم فقاعة الرسالة (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Exibir uma marca de seleção colorida para mensagens entregues em vez de nenhuma, para evitar o redimensionamento do balão de mensagem (@melvo)</li>
        </ul>
        <p>This release fixes the following bugs:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ar">يصلح هذا الإصدار العلل التالية:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca">Aquesta versió soluciona els errors següents:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">Esta versió soluciona els errors següents:</p>
        <p xml:lang="pt-BR">Esta versão corrige os seguintes bugs:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fix opening public MUC-based group chats via another XMPP client (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح فتح الدردشات الجماعية العامة القائمة على MUC عبر عميل XMPP آخر (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Corrigido o problema de abertura de bate-papos em grupo públicos baseados em MUC através de outro cliente XMPP (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix playing voice messages and changing playing position (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح تشغيل الرسائل الصوتية وتغيير موضع التشغيل (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção dos problemas na reprodução de mensagens de voz e na mudança de posição de jogo (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix updating message reactions that could not be sent instead of adding them a second time (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح تحديث تفاعلات الرسائل التي تعذر إرسالها بدلاً من إضافتها مرة ثانية (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção da atualização de reações de mensagens que não puderam ser enviadas em vez de adicioná-las uma segunda vez (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix updating group chat users in user interface (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح تحديث مستخدمي الدردشة الجماعية في واجهة المستخدم (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção da atualização de usuários de bate-papo em grupo na interface do usuário (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix displaying message reaction details (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح عرض تفاصيل تفاعل الرسالة (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção da exibição dos detalhes da reação da mensagem (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Update filtering contacts by labels even if label list is not open anymore (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">تحديث تصفية جهات الاتصال حسب اللصائق حتى لو لم تكن قائمة اللصائق مفتوحة بعد الآن (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Atualização da filtragem de contatos por marcadores, mesmo que a lista de marcadores não esteja mais aberta (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix scrolling media overview (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح تمرير نظرة الوسائط العامة (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção da rolagem na visão geral da mídia (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix updating draft messages (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح تحديث مسودات الرسائل (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção da atualização de mensagens em rascunho (@melvo)</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Kaidan requires Qt 6.6 now (@mlaurent, @melvo, @fazevedo, @plata)</p>
        <p xml:lang="ar">يتطلب كيدان الآن Qt 6.6 (@mlaurent, @melvo, @fazevedo, @plata)</p>
        <p xml:lang="pt-BR">O Kaidan agora requer Qt 6.6 (@mlaurent, @melvo, @fazevedo, @plata)</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release type="stable" version="0.10.1" date="2024-12-14T00:00:00Z">
      <description>
        <p>This release fixes the following bugs:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ar">يصلح هذا الإصدار العلل التالية:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca">Aquesta versió soluciona els errors següents:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">Esta versió soluciona els errors següents:</p>
        <p xml:lang="pt-BR">Esta versão corrige os seguintes bugs:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fix displaying files of each message in appropriate message bubble (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح عرض ملفات كل رسالة في فقاعة الرسالة المناسبة (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Corrigido o problema de exibição dos arquivos de cada mensagem no balão de mensagem apropriado (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix sending fallback messages for clients not supporting XEP-0447: Stateless file sharing (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح إرسال رسائل احتياطية للعملاء الذين لا يدعمون XEP-0447: Stateless file sharing (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção do envio de mensagens de fallback para clientes que não suportam XEP-0447: Compartilhamento de arquivos sem estado (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix margins within message bubbles (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح الهوامش داخل فقاعات الرسائل (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção das margens dentro dos balões de mensagem (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix hiding hidden message part (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح إخفاء الجزء المخفي من الرسالة (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção da parte oculta da mensagem (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix displaying marker for new messages (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح عرض العلامة للرسائل الجديدة (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Corrigido o problema de exibição do marcador para novas mensagens (@melvo)</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release type="stable" version="0.10.0" date="2024-12-09T00:00:00Z">
      <description>
        <p>This release adds the following features:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ar">يضيف هذا الإصدار الميزات التالية:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca">Aquesta versió afegeix les característiques següents:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">Esta versió afig les característiques següents:</p>
        <p xml:lang="pt-BR">Esta versão adiciona as seguintes funcionalidades:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ru">В этом выпуске добавлены следующие возможности:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Add server address completion (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إضافة إكمال عنوان الخادوم (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionado completamento de endereço do servidor (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li>Allow to edit account's profile (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">السماح بتحرير تشكيلة الحساب (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Permitir edição do perfil da conta (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li>Store and display delivery states of message reactions (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">تخزين وعرض حالات تسليم تفاعلات الرسائل (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Armazenar e exibir os estados de entrega das reações às mensagens (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Send pending message reactions after going online (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إرسال تفاعلات الرسائل المعلقة بعد الاتصال بالإنترنت (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Enviar reações a mensagens pendentes após entrar online (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Enable user to resend a message reaction if it previously failed (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">تمكين المستخدم من إعادة إرسال تفاعل رسالة إذا فشل سابقاً (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Permitir que o usuário reenvie uma resposta à mensagem caso ela tenha falhado anteriormente (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Open contact addition as page (mobile) or dialog (desktop) (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">فتح إضافة جهة اتصال كصفحة (للمحمول) أو حوار (للمكتب) (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Abrir adição de contato como página (dispositivo móvel) ou caixa de diálogo (desktop) (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Add option to open chat if contact exists on adding contact (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إضافة خيار لفتح الدردشة إذا كانت جهة الاتصال موجودة عند إضافتها (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionada opção para abrir o bate-papo se o contato já existir ao adicioná-lo (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Use consistent page with search bar for searching its content (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">استخدام صفحة متسقة مع شريط بحث للبحث في محتواها (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Usar uma página consistente com barra de pesquisa para pesquisar seu conteúdo (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Add local message removal (@taibsu)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إضافة إزالة الرسائل محلياً (@taibsu)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionada a remoção de mensagens locais (@taibsu)</li>
          <li>Allow reacting to own messages (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">السماح بالتفاعل مع الرسائل الخاصة (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Permitir reagir às próprias mensagens (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Add login option to chat (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إضافة خيار الولوج إلى الدردشة (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionada a opção de login ao bate-papo (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Display day of the week or "yesterday" for last messages (@taibsu, @melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">عرض يوم الأسبوع أو "أمس" لآخر الرسائل (@taibsu, @melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Exibir o dia da semana ou "ontem" para as últimas mensagens (@taibsu, @melvo)</li>
          <li>Add media overview (@fazevedo, @melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إضافة نظرة الوسائط العامة (@fazevedo, @melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionada a visão geral da mídia (@fazevedo, @melvo)</li>
          <li>Add contact list filtering by account and labels (i.e., roster groups) (incl. addition/removal) (@melvo, @tech-bash)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إضافة تصفية قائمة جهات الاتصال حسب الحساب واللصائق (أي مجموعات القائمة) (بما في ذلك الإضافة/الإزالة) (@melvo, @tech-bash)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionada a filtragem da lista de contatos por conta e rótulos (ou seja, grupos de contatos) (incluindo adição/remoção) (@melvo, @tech-bash)</li>
          <li>Add message date sections to chat (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إضافة أقسام تاريخ الرسائل إلى الدردشة (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionada seções de data de mensagens ao bate-papo (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Add support for automatic media downloads (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إضافة دعم لتنزيل الوسائط آلياً (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionado o suporte para downloads automáticos de mídia (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li>Add filtering contacts by availability (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إضافة تصفية جهات الاتصال حسب التوافر (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionado o filtro de contatos por disponibilidade (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Add item to contact list on first received direct message (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إضافة عنصر إلى قائمة جهات الاتصال عند استلام أول رسالة مباشرة (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionar item à lista de contatos na primeira mensagem direta recebida (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Add support for blocking chat addresses (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إضافة دعم لحظر عناوين الدردشة (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionado o suporte para bloquear endereços de bate-papo (@lnj)</li>
          <li>Improve notes chat (chat with oneself) usage (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">تحسين استخدام دردشة الملاحظات (الدردشة مع النفس) (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Melhoria do uso do bate-papo de notas (bate-papo consigo mesmo) (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Place avatar above chat address and name in account/contact details on narrow window (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">وضع الصورة الرمزية فوق عنوان الدردشة والاسم في تفاصيل الحساب/جهة الاتصال في النافذة الضيقة (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Colocar o avatar acima do endereço de bate-papo e do nome nos detalhes da conta/contato em uma janela estreita (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Reload camera device for QR code scanning as soon as it is plugged in / enabled (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إعادة تحميل جهاز الكاميرا لمسح رمز الاستجابة السريعة بمجرد وصله أو تفعيله (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Recarregar o dispositivo da câmera para leitura do código QR assim que ele for conectado/ativado (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Provide slider for QR code scanning to adjust camera zoom (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">توفير منزلق لمسح رمز الاستجابة السريعة لضبط تقريب الكاميرا (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionado um controle deslizante para leitura de código QR para ajustar o zoom da câmera (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Add contact to contact list on receiving presence subscription request (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إضافة جهة اتصال إلى القائمة عند استلام طلب اشتراك في التواجد (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionado contato à lista de contatos ao receber solicitação de assinatura de presença (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Add encryption key authentication via entering key IDs (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إضافة استيثاق مفتاح التعمية عبر إدخال معرفات المفاتيح (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionada autenticação por chave de criptografia inserindo IDs de chave (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Improve connecting to server and authentication (XEP-0388: Extensible SASL Profile (SASL 2), XEP-0386: Bind 2, XEP-0484: Fast Authentication Streamlining Tokens, XEP-0368: SRV records for XMPP over TLS) (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">تحسين الاتصال بالخادوم والاستيثاق (XEP-0388: Extensible SASL Profile (SASL 2)، وXEP-0386: Bind 2، وXEP-0484: Fast Authentication Streamlining Tokens، وXEP-0368: SRV records for XMPP over TLS) (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Melhoria da conexão com o servidor e a autenticação (XEP-0388: Perfil SASL extensível (SASL 2), XEP-0386: Bind 2, XEP-0484: Tokens de simplificação de autenticação rápida, XEP-0368: Registros SRV para XMPP sobre TLS) (@lnj)</li>
          <li>Support media sharing with more clients even for sharing multiple files at once (XEP-0447: Stateless file sharing v0.3) (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">دعم مشاركة الوسائط مع عملاء أكثر حتى عند مشاركة ملفات متعددة في وقت واحد (XEP-0447: Stateless file sharing v0.3) (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Suporte para compartilhamento de mídia com mais clientes, inclusive para compartilhamento de vários arquivos simultaneamente (XEP-0447: Compartilhamento de arquivos sem estado v0.3) (@lnj)</li>
          <li>Display and check media upload size limit (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">عرض والتحقق من حد حجم رفع الوسائط (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Exibir e verificar o limite de tamanho de upload de mídia (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li>Redesign message input field to use rounded corners and resized/symbolic buttons (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إعادة تصميم حقل إدخال الرسالة لاستخدام زوايا مدورة وأزرار رمزية مغيرة الحجم (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Redesenho do campo de entrada de mensagens para usar cantos arredondados e botões redimensionados/simbólicos (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Add support for moving account data to another account, informing contacts and restoring settings for moved contacts (XEP-0283: Moved) (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إضافة دعم لنقل بيانات الحساب إلى حساب آخر، وإخبار جهات الاتصال واستعادة الإعدادات لجهات الاتصال المنقولة (XEP-0283: Moved) (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionado suporte para mover dados de conta para outra conta, notificar os contatos e restaurar as configurações dos contatos movidos (XEP-0283: Movido) (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li>Add group chat support with invitations, user listing, participant mentioning and private/public group chat filtering (XEP-0369: Mediated Information eXchange (MIX), XEP-0405: Mediated Information eXchange (MIX): Participant Server Requirements, XEP-0406: Mediated Information eXchange (MIX): MIX Administration, XEP-0407: Mediated Information eXchange (MIX): Miscellaneous Capabilities) (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إضافة دعم الدردشة الجماعية مع الدعوات، وسرد المستخدمين، والإشارة للمشاركين وتصفية الدردشات الجماعية الخاصة/العامة (XEP-0369: Mediated Information eXchange (MIX)، وXEP-0405: Mediated Information eXchange (MIX): Participant Server Requirements، وXEP-0406: Mediated Information eXchange (MIX): MIX Administration، وXEP-0407: Mediated Information eXchange (MIX): Miscellaneous Capabilities) (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionado suporte para bate-papo em grupo com convites, lista de usuários, menção de participantes e filtragem de bate-papo em grupo privado/público (XEP-0369: Troca de Informações Mediada (MIX), XEP-0405: Troca de Informações Mediada (MIX): Requisitos do Servidor de Participantes, XEP-0406: Troca de Informações Mediada (MIX): Administração do MIX, XEP-0407: Troca de Informações Mediada (MIX): Recursos Diversos) (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Add button to cancel message correction (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إضافة زر لإلغاء تصحيح الرسالة (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionado botão para cancelar a correção da mensagem (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Display marker for new messages (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">عرض علامة للرسائل الجديدة (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Exibir marcador para novas mensagens (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Add enhanced account-wide and per contact notification settings depending on group chat mentions and presence (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إضافة إعدادات تنبيهات محسنة على مستوى الحساب ولكل جهة اتصال حسب الإشارات في الدردشة الجماعية والتواجد (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionadas configurações aprimoradas de notificação para toda a conta e por contato, dependendo de menções e presença no bate-papo em grupo (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Focus input fields appropriately (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">تركيز حقول الإدخال بشكل مناسب (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Focalizar os campos de entrada adequadamente (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Add support for replying to messages (XEP-0461: Message Replies) (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إضافة دعم للرد على الرسائل (XEP-0461: Message Replies) (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionado suporte para responder a mensagens (XEP-0461: Respostas a mensagens) (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Indicate that Kaidan is busy during account deletion and group chat actions (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إظهار أن كيدان مشغول أثناء حذف الحساب وإجراءات الدردشة الجماعية (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Indicar que Kaidan está ocupado durante a exclusão de contas e ações em grupos de bate-papo (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Hide account deletion button if In-Band Registration is not supported (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إخفاء زر حذف الحساب إذا كان التسجيل الداخلي غير مدعوم (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Ocultar botão de exclusão de conta se o registro na banda não for compatível (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Embed login area in page for QR code scanning and page for web registration instead of opening start page (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">تضمين منطقة الولوج في صفحة مسح رمز الاستجابة السريعة وصفحة التسجيل عبر الويب بدلاً من فتح صفحة البدء (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Incorporar a área de login na página para leitura do código QR e a página para cadastro na web em vez de abrir a página inicial (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Redesign onboarding user interface including new page for choosing provider to create account on (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إعادة تصميم واجهة المستخدم للتهيئة بما في ذلك صفحة جديدة لاختيار المزود لإنشاء حساب عليه (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Redesenho da interface de integração do usuário, incluindo uma nova página para escolher o provedor para criar uma conta (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Handle various corner cases that can occur during account creation (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">معالجة الحالات الحدية المختلفة التي قد تحدث أثناء إنشاء الحساب (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Tratamento de vários casos extremos que podem ocorrer durante a criação de contas (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Update to XMPP Providers v2 (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">التحديث إلى مزودي XMPP الإصدار 2 (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Atualização para provedores XMPP v2 (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Hide voice message button if uploading is not supported (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إخفاء زر الرسائل الصوتية إذا كان الرفع غير مدعوم (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Ocultar botão de mensagem de voz se o upload não for compatível (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Replace custom images for message delivery states with regular theme icons (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">استبدال الصور المخصصة لحالات تسليم الرسائل بأيقونات السمة القياسية (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Substituição das imagens personalizadas dos estados de entrega de mensagens pelos ícones padrão do tema (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Free up message content space by hiding unneeded avatars and increasing maximum message bubble width (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إخلاء مساحة لمحتوى الرسائل عبر إخفاء الصور الشخصية غير الضرورية وزيادة الحد الأقصى لعرض فقاعة الرسالة (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Liberar espaço no conteúdo da mensagem ocultando avatares desnecessários e aumentando a largura máxima do balão de mensagem (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Highlight draft message text to easily see what is not sent yet (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">تمييز نص مسودة الرسالة ليسهل رؤية ما لم يُرسل بعد (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Destaque o texto da mensagem em rascunho para ver facilmente o que ainda não foi enviado (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Store sent media in suitable directories with appropriate file extensions (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">تخزين الوسائط المرسلة في أدلة مناسبة مع امتدادات ملفات ملائمة (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Armazenar as mídias enviadas em diretórios adequados com as extensões de arquivo apropriadas (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Allow sending media with less steps from recording to sending (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">السماح بإرسال الوسائط بخطوات أقل من التسجيل إلى الإرسال (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Permitir o envio de mídia com menos etapas, da gravação ao envio (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Add media to be sent in scrollable area above message input field (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إضافة الوسائط المراد إرسالها في منطقة قابلة للتمرير فوق حقل إدخال الرسالة (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionar mídia para ser enviada na área rolável acima do campo de entrada de mensagem (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Display original images (if available) as previews instead of their thumbnails (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">عرض الصور الأصلية (إذا توفرت) كمعاينات بدلاً من مصغراتها (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Exibir as imagens originais (se disponíveis) como pré-visualizações em vez de suas miniaturas (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Display high resolution thumbnails for locally stored videos as previews instead of their thumbnails (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">عرض مصغرات عالية الدقة لمقاطع الفيديو المخزنة محلياً كمعاينات بدلاً من مصغراتها العادية (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Exibir miniaturas de alta resolução para vídeos armazenados localmente como pré-visualizações em vez de suas miniaturas (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Send smaller thumbnails (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إرسال مصغرات أصغر (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Enviar miniaturas menores (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Show camera status and reload camera once plugged in for taking pictures or recording videos (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إظهار حالة الكاميرا وإعادة تحميلها بمجرد وصلها لالتقاط الصور أو تسجيل الفيديو (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Mostrar o status da câmera e recarregar a câmera assim que ela for conectada para tirar fotos ou gravar vídeos (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Add zoom slider for taking pictures or recording videos (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إضافة منزلق تقريب لالتقاط الصور أو تسجيل الفيديو (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionado um controle deslizante de zoom para tirar fotos ou gravar vídeos (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Show overlay with description when files are dragged to be dropped on chats for being shared (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إظهار طبقة غطاء مع وصف عند سحب الملفات لإفلاتها في الدردشات لمشاركتها (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Exibir sobreposição com descrição quando arquivos forem arrastados e soltos em bate-papos para serem compartilhados (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Show location previews on a map (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إظهار معاينات الموقع الجغرافي على الخريطة (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Exibir pré-visualizações de localização em um mapa (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Open locations in user-defined way (system default, in-app, web) (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">فتح المواقع بالطريقة التي يحددها المستخدم (المبدئي للنظام، داخل التطبيق، الويب) (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Abrir locais de acordo com as configurações do usuário (padrão do sistema, no aplicativo, na web) (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Delete media that is only captured for sending but not sent (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">حذف الوسائط التي التُقطت للإرسال فقط ولم تُرسل (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Excluir mídias que foram capturadas apenas para envio, mas não enviadas (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Add voice message recorder to message input field (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إضافة مسجل رسائل صوتية إلى حقل إدخال الرسائل (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionado gravador de mensagens de voz ao campo de entrada de mensagens (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Add inline audio player (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إضافة مشغل صوتي مضمن (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionado reprodutor de áudio embutido (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Add context menu entry for opening directory of media files (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إضافة مدخل في القائمة السياقية لفتح دليل ملفات الوسائط (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionada entrada no menu de contexto para abrir o diretório de arquivos de mídia (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Show collapsible buttons to send media/locations inside of message input field (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إظهار أزرار قابلة للطي لإرسال الوسائط/المواقع داخل حقل إدخال الرسائل (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Exibir botões recolhíveis para enviar mídia/localizações dentro do campo de entrada de mensagem (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Move button for adding hidden message part to new collapsible button area (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">نقل زر إضافة جزء الرسالة المخفي إلى منطقة الأزرار الجديدة القابلة للطي (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Move botão para adicionar parte da mensagem oculta à nova área de botões recolhíveis (@melvo)</li>
        </ul>
        <p>This release fixes the following bugs:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ar">يصلح هذا الإصدار العلل التالية:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca">Aquesta versió soluciona els errors següents:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">Esta versió soluciona els errors següents:</p>
        <p xml:lang="pt-BR">Esta versão corrige os seguintes bugs:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fix index out of range error in message search (@taibsu)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح خطأ الفهرس خارج النطاق في البحث عن الرسائل (@taibsu)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção do erro de índice fora do intervalo na pesquisa de mensagens (@taibsu)</li>
          <li>Fix updating last message information in contact list (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح تحديث معلومات آخر رسالة في قائمة المتصلين (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Corrigido o problema de atualização das informações da última mensagem na lista de contatos (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix multiple corrections of the same message (@melvo, @taibsu)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح التصحيحات المتعددة لنفس الرسالة (@melvo، @taibsu)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção de múltiplas correções da mesma mensagem (@melvo, @taibsu)</li>
          <li>Request delivery receipts for pending messages (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">طلب إيصالات التسليم للرسائل المعلقة (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Solicitar confirmação de entrega para mensagens pendentes (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix sorting roster items (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح فرز عناصر قائمة المتصلين (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção da ordenação dos itens da lista (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix displaying spoiler messages (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح عرض رسائل حرق الأحداث (spoiler) (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção da exibição de mensagens com spoilers (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix displaying errors and encryption warnings for messages (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح عرض الأخطاء وتحذيرات التعمية للرسائل (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Corrigido o problema de exibição de erros e avisos de criptografia em mensagens (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix fetching messages from server's archive (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح جلب الرسائل من أرشيف الخادوم (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção do problema ao buscar mensagens do arquivo do servidor (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix various encryption problems (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح مشكلات تعمية مختلفة (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção de vários problemas de criptografia (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Send delivery receipts for caught up messages (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إرسال إيصالات التسليم للرسائل التي جُلبت مؤخراً (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Enviar confirmações de entrega para mensagens em atraso (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Do not hide last message date if contact name is too long (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">عدم إخفاء تاريخ آخر رسالة إذا كان اسم المتصل طويلاً جداً (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Não ocultar a data da última mensagem se o nome do contato for muito longo (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix displaying emojis (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح عرض الرموز التعبيرية (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção da exibição de emojis (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix several OMEMO bugs (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح عدة علل في بروتوكول OMEMO (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção de vários bugs do OMEMO (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Remove all locally stored data related to removed accounts (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إزالة كافة البيانات المخزنة محلياً والمتعلقة بالحسابات المحذوفة (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Remover todos os dados armazenados localmente relacionados às contas removidas (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix displaying media preview file names/sizes (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح عرض أسماء/أحجام ملفات معاينة الوسائط (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Corrigido o problema de exibição dos nomes/tamanhos dos arquivos de pré-visualização de mídia (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix disconnecting from server when application window is closed including timeout on connection problems (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح قطع الاتصال بالخادوم عند إغلاق نافذة التطبيق بما في ذلك مهلة مشكلات الاتصال (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção do problema de desconexão do servidor ao fechar a janela do aplicativo, incluindo tempo limite de conexão (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix media/location sharing (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح مشاركة الوسائط/الموقع الجغرافي (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção do compartilhamento de mídia/localização (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix handling emoji message reactions (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح التعامل مع تفاعلات الرموز التعبيرية على الرسائل (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção do tratamento de reações a mensagens com emojis (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix moving pinned chats (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح تحريك الدردشات المثبتة (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção da movimentação de bate-papos fixados (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li>Fix drag and drop for files and pasting them (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح سحب وإفلات الملفات ولصقها (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção do recurso de arrastar e soltar arquivos e colá-los (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix sending/displaying media in selected order (@lnj, @melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح إرسال/عرض الوسائط بالترتيب المحدد (@lnj، @melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção do envio/exibição de mídia na ordem selecionada (@lnj, @melvo)</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Kaidan is REUSE-compliant now</p>
        <p xml:lang="ar">كيدان متوافق مع معايير REUSE الآن</p>
        <p xml:lang="pt-BR">O Kaidan agora está em conformidade com o REUSE</p>
        <p>Kaidan requires Qt 5.15 and QXmpp 1.9 now</p>
        <p xml:lang="ar">يتطلب كيدان الإصدار 5.15 من Qt والإصدار 1.9 من QXmpp الآن</p>
        <p xml:lang="pt-BR">O Kaidan agora requer Qt 5.15 e QXmpp 1.9</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release type="stable" version="0.9.2" date="2024-07-24T00:00:00Z">
      <description>
        <p>This release fixes the following bugs:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ar">يصلح هذا الإصدار العلل التالية:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca">Aquesta versió soluciona els errors següents:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">Esta versió soluciona els errors següents:</p>
        <p xml:lang="pt-BR">Esta versão corrige os seguintes bugs:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fix file extension for downloads when mime type is empty (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح امتداد الملف للتنزيلات عندما يكون نوع MIME فارغاً (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção da extensão de arquivo para downloads quando o tipo MIME estiver vazio (@lnj)</li>
          <li>Fix file downloads without a source URL could be started (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح إمكانية بدء تنزيل الملفات بدون رابط مصدر (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção para downloads de arquivos sem URL de origem poder ser iniciada (@lnj)</li>
          <li>Fix file messages are never marked as sent (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح عدم وسم رسائل الملفات كمرسلة أبداً (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção das mensagens do arquivo nunca marcadas como enviadas (@lnj)</li>
          <li>Fix message body of previous file selection was used (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح استخدام متن الرسالة لاختيار الملف السابق (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção do corpo da mensagem de seleção de arquivo anterior (@lnj)</li>
          <li>Fix missing receipt request (for green checkmark) on media messages (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح طلب الإيصال المفقود (لعلامة الاختيار الخضراء) في رسائل الوسائط (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção da solicitação de recibo ausente (para marca de seleção verde) em mensagens de mídia (@lnj)</li>
          <li>Fix outgoing encrypted media messages are displayed as unencrypted (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح عرض رسائل الوسائط المعماة الصادرة كغير معماة (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção do problema em que as mensagens de mídia criptografadas enviadas são exibidas como não criptografadas (@lnj)</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release type="stable" version="0.9.1" date="2023-05-07T00:00:00Z"/>
    <release type="stable" version="0.9.0" date="2023-04-30T00:00:00Z">
      <description>
        <p>This release adds the following features:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ar">يضيف هذا الإصدار الميزات التالية:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca">Aquesta versió afegeix les característiques següents:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">Esta versió afig les característiques següents:</p>
        <p xml:lang="pt-BR">Esta versão adiciona as seguintes funcionalidades:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ru">В этом выпуске добавлены следующие возможности:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>New message bubble design based on Tok's code (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">تصميم جديد لفقاعة الرسالة مبني على شفرة Tok (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Novo design de balão de mensagem baseado no código do Tok (@lnj)</li>
          <li>Group messages from same author (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">تجميع الرسائل من نفس الكاتب (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Agrupar mensagens do mesmo autor (@lnj)</li>
          <li>Introduce machine-readable DOAP file describing Kaidan's XMPP compliance (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">تقديم ملف DOAP مقروء آلياً يصف توافق كيدان مع XMPP (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Introduzir arquivo DOAP legível por máquina descrevendo a conformidade do Kaidan com XMPP (@melvo)</li>
          <li>New chat background picture (@raghu)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">صورة خلفية جديدة للدردشة (@raghu)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Nova imagem de fundo do bate-papo (@raghu)</li>
          <li>OMEMO 2 support with easy trust management (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">دعم OMEMO 2 مع إدارة سهلة للثقة (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Suporte a OMEMO 2 com gerenciamento de confiança simplificado (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Read markers (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">علامات القراءة (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Ler os marcadores (@melvo)</li>
          <li>The chat page title can be clicked to open the user's profile now (@mbruchert)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">يمكن النقر على عنوان صفحة الدردشة لفتح ملف المستخدم الشخصي الآن (@mbruchert)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Agora é possível clicar no título da página de bate-papo para abrir o perfil do usuário (@mbruchert)</li>
          <li>Support file sharing with multiple files per message, thumbnails and end-to-end encryption (@lnj, @jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">دعم مشاركة الملفات بملفات متعددة لكل رسالة، والمصغرات والتعمية بين الطرفين (@lnj، @jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Suporte para compartilhamento de arquivos com múltiplos arquivos por mensagem, miniaturas e criptografia de ponta a ponta (@lnj, @jbbgameich)</li>
          <li>Restore window position on start (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">استعادة موضع النافذة عند البدء (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Restaurar a posição da janela ao iniciar (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Chat pinning (@melvo, @tech-bash)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">تثبيت الدردشات (@melvo، @tech-bash)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Fixar bate-papo (@melvo, @tech-bash)</li>
          <li>Emoji message reactions (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">تفاعلات الرموز التعبيرية على الرسائل (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Reações de mensagem com emoji (@melvo)</li>
          <li>The message search now also works with messages that are not displayed (@taibsu)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">البحث عن الرسائل يعمل الآن أيضاً مع الرسائل غير المعروضة (@taibsu)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">A busca de mensagens agora também funciona com mensagens que não são exibidas (@taibsu)</li>
          <li>Public group chat search (without group chat support yet) (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">البحث عن الدردشات الجماعية العامة (بدون دعم الدردشة الجماعية بعد) (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Busca de bate-papo em grupo público (ainda sem suporte para bate-papo em grupo) (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li>Account settings with ability to change avatar and profile information (@taibsu)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إعدادات الحساب مع القدرة على تغيير الصورة الشخصية ومعلومات الملف الشخصي (@taibsu)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Configurações da conta com possibilidade de alterar o avatar e as informações do perfil (@taibsu)</li>
          <li>Redesign of settings, redesign of user profiles as sheet instead of page (@mbruchert)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إعادة تصميم الإعدادات، وإعادة تصميم ملفات تعريف المستخدمين كصحيفة بدلاً من صفحة (@mbruchert)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Redesenho das configurações, redesenho dos perfis de usuário como planilha em vez de página (@mbruchert)</li>
          <li>Store message drafts locally (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">تخزين مسودات الرسائل محلياً (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Armazenar rascunhos de mensagens localmente (@fazevedo)</li>
        </ul>
        <p>We switched from Weblate to the KDE translation system</p>
        <p xml:lang="ar">انتقلنا من Weblate إلى نظام ترجمة كيداي</p>
        <p xml:lang="pt-BR">Migramos do Weblade para o sistema de tradução KDE</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release type="stable" version="0.8.0" date="2021-05-28T00:00:00Z">
      <description>
        <p>This release adds the following features:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ar">يضيف هذا الإصدار الميزات التالية:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca">Aquesta versió afegeix les característiques següents:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">Esta versió afig les característiques següents:</p>
        <p xml:lang="pt-BR">Esta versão adiciona as seguintes funcionalidades:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ru">В этом выпуске добавлены следующие возможности:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Add typing notifications (XEP-0085: Chat State Notifications) (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إضافة تنبيهات الكتابة (XEP-0085: تنبيهات حالة الدردشة) (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionadas notificações de digitação (XEP-0085: Notificações de estado do bate-papo) (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li>Add message history syncing (XEP-0313: Message Archive Management) (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إضافة مزامنة تأريخ الرسائل (XEP-0313: إدارة أرشيف الرسائل) (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionada sincronização do histórico de mensagens (XEP-0313: Gerenciamento de Arquivo de Mensagens) (@lnj)</li>
          <li>Window size is restored (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">استُعيد حجم النافذة (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">O tamanho da janela é restaurado (@melvo)</li>
          <li>The server's website link is displayed if account creation is disabled (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">رابط موقع الخادوم يُعرض إذا كان إنشاء الحساب معطلاً (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">O link do site do servidor é exibido se a criação de conta estiver desativada (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Use breeze theme on macOS (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">استخدام سمة Breeze على نظام macOS (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Usar o tema Breeze no macOS (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li>Improved user strings &amp; descriptions (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">تحسين سلاسل الوصف والنصوص للمستخدم (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Strings &amp; descrições de usuário aprimoradas (@melvo)</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release type="stable" version="0.7.0" date="2021-02-02T00:00:00Z">
      <description>
        <p>This release adds the following features:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ar">يضيف هذا الإصدار الميزات التالية:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca">Aquesta versió afegeix les característiques següents:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">Esta versió afig les característiques següents:</p>
        <p xml:lang="pt-BR">Esta versão adiciona as seguintes funcionalidades:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ru">В этом выпуске добавлены следующие возможности:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Display client information (name, version, OS) of contacts (@jbbgameich, @lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">عرض معلومات العميل (الاسم، الإصدار، نظام التشغيل) لجهات الاتصال (@jbbgameich، @lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Exibir informações do cliente (nome, versão, SO) dos contatos (@jbbgameich, @lnj)</li>
          <li>Drag'n'drop for sending files (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">السحب والإفلات لإرسال الملفات (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Arrastar e soltar para enviar arquivos (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li>Allow pasting images from the clipboard (Ctrl+Shift+V) into the chat (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">السماح بلصق الصور من الحافظة (Ctrl+Shift+V) في الدردشة (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Permitir colar imagens da área de transferência (Ctrl+Shift+V) no bate-papo (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li>Allow inserting newlines using Shift+Enter (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">السماح بإدراج أسطر جديدة باستخدام Shift+Enter (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Permitir a inserção de novas linhas usando Shift+Enter (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li>Add configuration of custom hostname/port (@jbbgameich, @melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إضافة ضبط لاسم المضيف/المنفذ المخصص (@jbbgameich، @melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionada configuração de nome de host/porta personalizados (@jbbgameich, @melvo)</li>
          <li>Favourite emojis are shown by default now (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">الرموز التعبيرية المفضلة تُعرض مبدئياً الآن (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Os emojis favoritos agora são exibidos por padrão (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Search emojis after entering colon (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">البحث عن الرموز التعبيرية بعد إدخال النقطتين الرأسيتين (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Pesquisar emojis após inserir dois pontos (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Display connection errors in the global drawer after login (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">عرض أخطاء الاتصال في الدرج العالمي بعد الولوج (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Exibir erros de conexão no menu lateral global após o login (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Improved design of media preview sheets (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">تحسين تصميم صحائف معاينة الوسائط (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Melhoria no design das folhas de pré-visualização de mídia (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li>Restructure message sending bar (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إعادة هيكلة شريط إرسال الرسائل (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Reestruturação da barra de envio de mensagens (@melvo)</li>
        </ul>
        <p>This release fixes the following bugs:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ar">يصلح هذا الإصدار العلل التالية:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca">Aquesta versió soluciona els errors següents:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">Esta versió soluciona els errors següents:</p>
        <p xml:lang="pt-BR">Esta versão corrige os seguintes bugs:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Do not interpret random URLs as files anymore (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">عدم تفسير الروابط العشوائية كملفات بعد الآن (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Não interpretar mais URLs aleatórias como arquivos (@lnj)</li>
          <li>Fix the style of buttons when using Material style (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح نمط الأزرار عند استخدام نمط Material (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção do estilo dos botões ao usar o estilo Material (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix file dialog and media drawer opening in some cases (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح فتح حوار الملف ودرج الوسائط في بعض الحالات (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Corrigido o problema de abertura da caixa de diálogo de arquivos e da gaveta de mídia em alguns casos (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix opening of the LoginPage when scanning QR code without password (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح فتح صفحة الولوج عند مسح رمز الاستجابة السريعة بدون كلمة مرور (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Corrigido o problema que impedia a abertura da página de login ao escanear o código QR sem senha (@melvo)</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Kaidan requires Qt 5.14 now</p>
        <p xml:lang="ar">يتطلب كيدان الإصدار 5.14 من Qt الآن</p>
        <p xml:lang="pt-BR">O Kaidan agora requer o Qt 5.14</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release type="stable" version="0.6.0" date="2020-08-20T00:00:00Z">
      <description>
        <p>This release adds the following features:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ar">يضيف هذا الإصدار الميزات التالية:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca">Aquesta versió afegeix les característiques següents:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">Esta versió afig les característiques següents:</p>
        <p xml:lang="pt-BR">Esta versão adiciona as seguintes funcionalidades:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ru">В этом выпуске добавлены следующие возможности:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>When offline, messages are cached now to be sent later (@yugubich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">عند عدم الاتصال، تُخزن الرسائل في الخبيئة الآن لتُرسل لاحقاً (@yugubich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Quando estiver offline, as mensagens são armazenadas em cache para serem enviadas posteriormente (@yugubich)</li>
          <li>It's allowed to also correct other messages than the last one now (@yugubich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">يُسمح الآن بتصحيح رسائل أخرى غير الرسالة الأخيرة (@yugubich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Agora também é permitido corrigir outras mensagens além da última (@yugubich)</li>
          <li>Also pending (unsent) messages can be corrected now (@yugubich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">يمكن الآن أيضاً تصحيح الرسائل المعلقة (غير المرسلة) (@yugubich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Mensagens pendentes (não enviadas) também podem ser corrigidas agora (@yugubich)</li>
          <li>Chats can be opened from the notifications now (@melvo, @jbbgameich, @cacahueto)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">يمكن فتح الدردشات من التنبيهات الآن (@melvo، @jbbgameich، @cacahueto)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Agora é possível abrir bate-papos a partir das notificações (@melvo, @jbbgameich, @cacahueto)</li>
          <li>New option to permanently hide your password in Kaidan (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">خيار جديد لإخفاء كلمة المرور بشكل دائم في كيدان (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Nova opção para ocultar permanentemente sua senha no Kaidan (@melvo)</li>
          <li>New buttons for easily copying your jid and password (@jbbgameich, @fazevedo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">أزرار جديدة لنسخ JID وكلمة المرور بسهولة (@jbbgameich، @fazevedo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Novos botões para copiar facilmente seu jid e senha (@jbbgameich, @fazevedo)</li>
          <li>Moved account management pages into the settings (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">نُقلت صفحات إدارة الحساب إلى الإعدادات (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Páginas de gerenciamento de conta movida para as configurações (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li>The cursor is moved to the end of the text field when correcting a message now (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">يُنقل المؤشر إلى نهاية حقل النص عند تصحيح الرسالة الآن (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Agora, ao corrigir uma mensagem, o cursor é movido para o final do campo de texto (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Scanning QR codes without a password works now and results in only the JID being set (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">مسح رموز الاستجابة السريعة بدون كلمة مرور يعمل الآن ويؤدي لضبط JID فقط (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">A leitura de códigos QR sem senha agora funciona e resulta na configuração apenas do JID (@melvo)</li>
          <li>The roster is called contact list now (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">قائمة الأسماء (roster) تسمى قائمة المتصلين الآن (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">A lista agora se chama lista de contatos (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li>The resource for the displayed presence is picked with fixed rules now (it was random before which resource is displayed) (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">يُختار مورد الحضور المعروض بقواعد ثابتة الآن (كان اختيار المورد المعروض عشوائياً في السابق) (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">O recurso para a presença exibido agora é escolhido com regras fixas (antes era aleatório qual recurso era exibido) (@lnj)</li>
          <li>Handle notifications differently on GNOME to keep them in the notifications area (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">معالجة التنبيهات بشكل مختلف في جنوم لإبقائها في منطقة التنبيهات (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Gerencia as notificações de forma diferente no GNOME para mantê-las na área de notificações (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Switched to the upstream HTTP File Upload implementation (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">الانتقال إلى تطبيق رفع ملفات HTTP الرسمي (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Alteração da implementação upstream de Upload de Arquivos HTTP (@lnj)</li>
          <li>Code refactoring and partial rewrite of the following classes: Kaidan, ClientWorker, RosterManager, PresenceCache, DownloadManager, TransferCache, QrCodeDecoder (@lnj, @jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إعادة هيكلة الشفرة وإعادة كتابة جزئية للأصناف التالية: Kaidan، وClientWorker، وRosterManager، وPresenceCache، وDownloadManager، وTransferCache، وQrCodeDecoder (@lnj، @jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Refatoração de código e reescrita parcial das seguintes classes: Kaidan, ClientWorker, RosterManager, PresenceCache, DownloadManager, TransferCache, QrCodeDecoder (@lnj, @jbbgameich)</li>
        </ul>
        <p>This release fixes the following bugs:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ar">يصلح هذا الإصدار العلل التالية:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca">Aquesta versió soluciona els errors següents:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">Esta versió soluciona els errors següents:</p>
        <p xml:lang="pt-BR">Esta versão corrige os seguintes bugs:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Playback issues in media video preview (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">مشكلات التشغيل في معاينة فيديو الوسائط (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Problemas de reprodução na pré-visualização de vídeo (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li>Messages sent from other of your devices are displayed as they were sent by the chat partner (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">الرسائل المرسلة من أجهزتك الأخرى تُعرض كما لو كانت مرسلة من شريك الدردشة (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">As mensagens enviadas de outros dispositivos seus são exibidas da mesma forma que foram enviadas pelo parceiro de bate-papo (@lnj).</li>
          <li>Notifications are shown persistently on the screen (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">تُعرض التنبيهات بشكل مستمر على الشاشة (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">As notificações são exibidas persistentemente na tela (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li>Roster names are not updated in the database (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">أسماء قائمة المتصلين لا تُحدث في قاعدة البيانات (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Nomes listados não atualizados no banco de dados (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Roster items are not updated in the model correctly (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">عناصر قائمة المتصلين لا تُحدث في النموذج بشكل صحيح (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Os itens da lista não estão sendo atualizados corretamente no modelo (@melvo)</li>
          <li>All sheets contain two headers: It uses the new built-in header property now (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">كافة الصحائف تحتوي على ترويستين: تستخدم خاصية الترويسة المدمجة الجديدة الآن (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Todas as planilhas contêm dois cabeçalhos: Agora utiliza a nova propriedade de cabeçalho integrada (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li>Unreadable buttons with white text on with background in some styles (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">أزرار غير مقروءة بنص أبيض على خلفية بيضاء في بعض الأنماط (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Botões ilegíveis com texto branco sobre fundo em alguns estilos (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li>Database version isn't saved correctly (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصدار قاعدة البيانات لا يُحفظ بشكل صحيح (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">A versão do banco de dados não está sendo salva corretamente (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Errors when building with newer ZXing versions (@vkrause)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">أخطاء عند البناء باستخدام إصدارات أحدث من ZXing (@vkrause)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Erros ao compilar com versões mais recentes do ZXing (@vkrause)</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Kaidan requires a C++17-compliant compiler now</p>
        <p xml:lang="ar">يتطلب كيدان مترجماً متوافقاً مع C++17 الآن</p>
        <p xml:lang="pt-BR">O Kaidan agora requer um compilador compatível com C++17</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release type="stable" version="0.5.0" date="2020-04-04T00:00:00Z">
      <description>
        <p>This release adds the following features:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ar">يضيف هذا الإصدار الميزات التالية:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca">Aquesta versió afegeix les característiques següents:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">Esta versió afig les característiques següents:</p>
        <p xml:lang="pt-BR">Esta versão adiciona as seguintes funcionalidades:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ru">В этом выпуске добавлены следующие возможности:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Add parsing of XMPP URIs (@lnj, @melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إضافة تحليل روابط XMPP (@lnj، @melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionada análise de URIs XMPP (@lnj, @melvo)</li>
          <li>Add QR code scanning and generation (@lnj, @jbbgameich, @melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إضافة مسح وتوليد رموز الاستجابة السريعة (@lnj، @jbbgameich، @melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionada leitura e geração de código QR (@lnj, @jbbgameich, @melvo)</li>
          <li>Add contact search (@zatrox, @lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إضافة البحث عن المتصلين (@zatrox، @lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionada pesquisa de contatos (@zatrox, @lnj)</li>
          <li>Add muting notifications for messages of contacts (@zatrox)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إضافة كتم التنبيهات لرسائل المتصلين (@zatrox)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionada a opção de silenciar notificações para mensagens de contatos (@zatrox)</li>
          <li>Add renaming contacts (@lnj, @zatrox, @melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إضافة إعادة تسمية المتصلين (@lnj، @zatrox، @melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionada renomeação de contatos (@lnj, @zatrox, @melvo)</li>
          <li>Show user profile information (@lnj, @jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إظهار معلومات ملف المستخدم الشخصي (@lnj، @jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Mostrar informações do perfil do usuário (@lnj, @jbbgameich)</li>
          <li>Add extended multimedia support (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إضافة دعم ممتد للوسائط المتعددة (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionado suporte multimídia estendido (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li>Add message search (@yugubich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إضافة البحث عن الرسائل (@yugubich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionada pesquisa de mensagens (@yugubich)</li>
          <li>Redesign contact list, text avatar, counter for unread messages, chat page, chat message bubble (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إعادة تصميم قائمة المتصلين، والصورة الشخصية النصية، وعداد الرسائل غير المقروءة، وصفحة الدردشة، وفقاعة رسالة الدردشة (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Redesenho da lista de contatos, avatar de texto, contador de mensagens não lidas, página de bate-papo, balão de mensagem de bate-papo (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Show notifications on Android (@melvo, @jbbgameich, @cacahueto)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إظهار التنبيهات على أندرويد (@melvo، @jbbgameich، @cacahueto)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Mostrar notificações no Android (@melvo, @jbbgameich, @cacahueto)</li>
          <li>Add option for enabling or disabling an account temporarily (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إضافة خيار لتمكين أو تعطيل حساب بشكل مؤقت (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionada opção para ativar ou desativar uma conta temporariamente (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Refactor login screen with hints for invalid credentials and better usage of keyboard keys (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إعادة هيكلة شاشة الولوج مع تلميحات لبيانات الاستيثاق غير الصالحة واستخدام أفضل لمفاتيح لوحة المفاتيح (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Reformulação da tela de login com dicas para credenciais inválidas e melhor uso das teclas do teclado (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Add message quoting (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إضافة اقتباس الرسائل (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionada mensagem de citação (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li>Truncate very long messages to avoid crashing Kaidan or using it to full capacity (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">تقصير الرسائل الطويلة جداً لتجنب انهيار كيدان أو استهلاكه لكامل السعة (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Truncar mensagens muito longas para evitar travamentos do Kaidan ou o uso de sua capacidade máxima (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li>Add button with link for issue tracking to about page (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إضافة زر مع رابط لتتبع المشكلات إلى صفحة "عن" (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionado botão com link para rastreamento de problemas à página "Sobre" (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Improve messages for connection errors (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">تحسين رسائل أخطاء الاتصال (@melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Melhoria das mensagens para erros de conexão (@melvo)</li>
          <li>Add account deletion (@melvo, @mbruchert)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إضافة حذف الحساب (@melvo، @mbruchert)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionada exclusão de conta (@melvo, @mbruchert)</li>
          <li>Redesign logo and global drawer banner (@melvo, @mbruchert)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إعادة تصميم الشعار ولافتة الدرج العالمي (@melvo، @mbruchert)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Redesenho do logotipo e do banner global da gaveta (@melvo, @mbruchert)</li>
          <li>Add onboarding with registration, normal login and QR code login (@melvo, @lnj, @jbbgameich, @mbruchert)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إضافة تهيئة مع التسجيل، والولوج العادي والولوج عبر رمز الاستجابة السريعة (@melvo، @lnj، @jbbgameich، @mbruchert)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionada integração com registro, login normal e login por código QR (@melvo, @lnj, @jbbgameich, @mbruchert)</li>
          <li>Add OARS rating (@nickrichards)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إضافة تقييم OARS (@nickrichards)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionada classificação OARS (@nickrichards)</li>
          <li>Add secondary roster sorting by contact name (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إضافة فرز ثانوي لقائمة المتصلين حسب اسم المتصل (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionada classificação secundária da lista por nome de contato (@lnj)</li>
          <li>Add support for recording audio and video messages (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إضافة دعم لتسجيل الرسائل الصوتية والمرئية (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionado suporte para gravação de mensagens de áudio e vídeo (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li>Add Kaidan to KDE's F-Droid repository (@nicolasfella)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إضافة كيدان إلى مستودع F-Droid التابع لكيداي (@nicolasfella)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionado o Kaidan ao repositório F-Droid do KDE @nicolasfella)</li>
          <li>Improve build scripts for better cross-platform support (@jbbgameich, @cacahueto, @lnj, @mauro)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">تحسين سكريبتات البناء لدعم أفضل للمنصات المتعددة (@jbbgameich، @cacahueto، @lnj، @mauro)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Melhoria dos scripts de compilação para melhor suporte multiplataforma (@jbbgameich, @cacahueto, @lnj, @mauro)</li>
          <li>Refactor code for better performance and stability (@lnj, @jbbgameich, @melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إعادة هيكلة الشفرة لتحسين الأداء والاستقرار (@lnj، @jbbgameich، @melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Refatoração do código para melhor desempenho e estabilidade (@lnj, @jbbgameich, @melvo)</li>
          <li>Add documentation to achieve easier maintenance (@melvo, @lnj, @jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إضافة وثائق لتحقيق صيانة أسهل (@melvo، @lnj، @jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionada documentação para facilitar a manutenção (@melvo, @lnj, @jbbgameich)</li>
        </ul>
        <p>This release fixes the following bugs:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ar">يصلح هذا الإصدار العلل التالية:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca">Aquesta versió soluciona els errors següents:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">Esta versió soluciona els errors següents:</p>
        <p xml:lang="pt-BR">Esta versão corrige os seguintes bugs:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fix AppImage build (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح بناء AppImage (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção da compilação do AppImage (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li>Fix scrolling and item height problems in settings (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح مشكلات التمرير وارتفاع العناصر في الإعدادات (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção de problemas de rolagem e altura dos itens nas configurações (@jbbgameich)</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Require Qt 5.12 and QXmpp 1.2</p>
        <p xml:lang="ar">يتطلب Qt 5.12 وQXmpp 1.2</p>
        <p xml:lang="pt-BR">Requer Qt 5.12 e QXmpp 1.2</p>
        <p>Drop Ubuntu Touch support due to outdated Qt</p>
        <p xml:lang="ar">إسقاط دعم Ubuntu Touch بسبب إصدار Qt القديم</p>
        <p xml:lang="pt-BR">O suporte ao Ubuntu Touch foi descontinuado devido ao Qt desatualizado</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release type="stable" version="0.4.2" date="2020-04-02T00:00:00Z">
      <description>
        <p>This release adds the following features:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ar">يضيف هذا الإصدار الميزات التالية:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca">Aquesta versió afegeix les característiques següents:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">Esta versió afig les característiques següents:</p>
        <p xml:lang="pt-BR">Esta versão adiciona as seguintes funcionalidades:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ru">В этом выпуске добавлены следующие возможности:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>ChatMessage: Do not display media URLs (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">رسالة دردشة: عدم عرض روابط الوسائط (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">ChatMessage: Não exibir URLs de mídia (@lnj)</li>
          <li>ChatMessage: Add media URL copy action (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">رسالة دردشة: إضافة إجراء نسخ رابط الوسائط (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">ChatMessage: Adicionada ação de copiar URL de mídia (@lnj)</li>
        </ul>
        <p>This release fixes the following bugs:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ar">يصلح هذا الإصدار العلل التالية:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca">Aquesta versió soluciona els errors següents:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">Esta versió soluciona els errors següents:</p>
        <p xml:lang="pt-BR">Esta versão corrige os seguintes bugs:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fix roster not cleared when switching account (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح عدم مسح قائمة المتصلين عند تبديل الحساب (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Corrigido o problema de lista não ser limpa ao trocar de conta (@lnj)</li>
          <li>ChatMessage: Fix copy to clipboard function (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">رسالة دردشة: إصلاح وظيفة النسخ إلى الحافظة (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">ChatMessage: Correção da função de copiar para a área de transferência (@lnj)</li>
          <li>Fix scroll indiciator not overlap message on the right edge (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح عدم تداخل مؤشر التمرير مع الرسالة على الحافة اليمنى (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção do indicador de rolagem para que a mensagem não se sobreponha à borda direita (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li>Fix upload issues (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح مشكلات الرفع (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção de problemas de upload (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li>ChatPage: Clear message correction when sent (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">صفحة الدردشة: مسح تصحيح الرسالة عند الإرسال (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">ChatPage: Limpar correção de mensagem ao enviar (@fazevedo)</li>
          <li>Fix roster sorting (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح فرز قائمة المتصلين (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção da ordenação da lista (@lnj)</li>
          <li>Fix buttonTextColor deprecation warnings (@sredman)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح تحذيرات إهمال buttonTextColor (@sredman)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção dos avisos de descontinuação de buttonTextColor (@sredman)</li>
          <li>Fix build with QXmpp &gt;= 1.0.1 (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح البناء مع الإصدار 1.0.1 من QXmpp أو أحدث (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção de compilação com QXmpp &gt;= 1.0.1 (@lnj)</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release type="stable" version="0.4.1" date="2019-07-16T00:00:00Z">
      <description>
        <p>This release fixes the following bugs:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ar">يصلح هذا الإصدار العلل التالية:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca">Aquesta versió soluciona els errors següents:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">Esta versió soluciona els errors següents:</p>
        <p xml:lang="pt-BR">Esta versão corrige os seguintes bugs:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fix SSL problems for AppImage (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح مشكلات SSL لـ AppImage (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção de problemas de SSL para AppImage (@lnj)</li>
          <li>Fix connection problems (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح مشكلات الاتصال (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção de problemas de conexão (@lnj)</li>
          <li>Keep QXmpp v0.8.3 compatibility (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">الحفاظ على التوافق مع QXmpp الإصدار 0.8.3 (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Mantida compatibilidade com QXmpp v0.8.3 (@lnj)</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release type="stable" version="0.4.0" date="2019-07-08T00:00:00Z">
      <description>
        <p>This release adds the following features:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ar">يضيف هذا الإصدار الميزات التالية:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca">Aquesta versió afegeix les característiques següents:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">Esta versió afig les característiques següents:</p>
        <p xml:lang="pt-BR">Esta versão adiciona as seguintes funcionalidades:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ru">В этом выпуске добавлены следующие возможности:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Show proper notifications using KNotifications (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إظهار تنبيهات مناسبة باستخدام KNotifications (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Exibir notificações adequadas usando KNotifications (@lnj)</li>
          <li>Add settings page for changing passwords (@jbbgameich, @lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إضافة صفحة إعدادات لتغيير كلمات المرور (@jbbgameich، @lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionada página de configurações para alterar senhas (@jbbgameich, @lnj)</li>
          <li>Add XEP-0352: Client State Indication (gloox/QXmpp) (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إضافة XEP-0352: بيان حالة العميل (gloox/QXmpp) (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionado XEP-0352: Indicação de estado do cliente (gloox/QXmpp) (@lnj)</li>
          <li>Add media/file (including GIFs) sharing (@lnj, @jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إضافة مشاركة الوسائط/الملفات (بما في ذلك صور GIF) (@lnj، @jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionado compartilhamento de mídia/arquivo (incluindo GIFs) (@lnj, @jbbgameich)</li>
          <li>Full back-end rewrite to QXmpp (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إعادة كتابة الواجهة الخلفية بالكامل باستخدام QXmpp (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Reescrita completa do back-end para QXmpp (@lnj)</li>
          <li>Implement XEP-0363: HTTP File Upload and UploadManager for QXmpp (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">تطبيق XEP-0363: رفع ملفات HTTP وUploadManager لـ QXmpp (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Implementado XEP-0363: Upload de arquivos HTTP e UploadManager para QXmpp (@lnj)</li>
          <li>Use XEP-0280: Message Carbons from QXmpp (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">استخدام XEP-0280: كربون الرسائل من QXmpp (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Usar XEP-0280: Enviar mensagens de carbono do QXmpp (@lnj)</li>
          <li>Use XEP-0352: Client State Indication from QXmpp (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">استخدام XEP-0352: بيان حالة العميل من QXmpp (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Usar XEP-0352: Indicação de estado do cliente do QXmpp (@lnj)</li>
          <li>Check incoming messages for media links (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">فحص الرسائل الواردة بحثاً عن روابط الوسائط (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Verificar as mensagens recebidas para links de mídia (@lnj)</li>
          <li>Implement XEP-0308: Last Message Correction (@lnj, @jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">تطبيق XEP-0308: تصحيح آخر رسالة (@lnj، @jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Implementado XEP-0308: Última correção de mensagem (@lnj, @jbbgameich)</li>
          <li>Make attachments downloadable (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">جعل المرفقات قابلة للتنزيل (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Tornar os anexos disponíveis para download (@lnj)</li>
          <li>Implement XEP-0382: Spoiler messages (@xavi)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">تطبيق XEP-0382: رسائل حرق الأحداث (@xavi)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Implementado XEP-0382: Mensagens com spoiler (@xavi)</li>
          <li>Kaidan is now offline usable (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">كيدان قابل للاستخدام بدون اتصال الآن (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">O Kaidan agora está utilizável offline (@lnj)</li>
          <li>Kaidan is able to open xmpp: URIs (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">كيدان قادر على فتح روابط xmpp: (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">O Kaidan consegue abrir URIs xmpp: (@lnj)</li>
          <li>New logo (@ilyabizyaev)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">شعار جديد (@ilyabizyaev)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Novo logotipo (@ilyabizyaev)</li>
          <li>Show presence information of contacts (@lnj, @melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إظهار معلومات الحضور للمتصلين (@lnj، @melvo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Mostrar informações de presença dos contatos (@lnj, @melvo)</li>
          <li>Add EmojiPicker from Spectral with search and favorites functionality (@jbbgameich, @fazevedo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إضافة EmojiPicker من Spectral مع وظائف البحث والمفضلة (@jbbgameich، @fazevedo)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionado o EmojiPicker da Spectral com funcionalidade de busca e favoritos (@jbbgameich, @fazevedo)</li>
          <li>Highlight links in chat and make links clickable (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">تمييز الروابط في الدردشة وجعلها قابلة للنقر (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Destacar links no bate-papo e torná-los clicáveis ​​(@lnj)</li>
          <li>New about dialog instead of the about page (@ilyabizyaev)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">حوار "عن" جديد بدلاً من صفحة "عن" (@ilyabizyaev)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Novo diálogo "Sobre" em vez da página "Sobre" (@ilyabizyaev)</li>
          <li>Add image preview in chat and before sending (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إضافة معاينة الصور في الدردشة وقبل الإرسال (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionada uma pré-visualização da imagem no bate-papo e antes de enviar (@lnj)</li>
          <li>Send messages on Enter, new line on Ctrl-Enter (@ilyabizyaev)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إرسال الرسائل عند الضغط على Enter، وسطر جديد عند Ctrl-Enter (@ilyabizyaev)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Enviar mensagens com Enter, nova linha com Ctrl+Enter (@ilyabizyaev)</li>
          <li>'Add contact' is now the main action on the contacts page (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إجراء 'إضافة متصل' هو الإجراء الرئيسي في صفحة المتصلين الآن (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">'Adicionar contato' agora é a ação principal na página de contatos (@lnj)</li>
          <li>Elide contact names and messages in roster (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">تقصير أسماء المتصلين والرسائل في قائمة المتصلين (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Omitir nomes de contato e mensagens na lista (@lnj)</li>
          <li>Chat page redesign (@ilyabizyaev)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إعادة تصميم صفحة الدردشة (@ilyabizyaev)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Redesenho da página de bate-papo (@ilyabizyaev)</li>
          <li>Display passive notifications when trying to use online actions while offline (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">عرض تنبيهات سلبية عند محاولة استخدام إجراءات تتطلب الاتصال أثناء عدم الاتصال (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Exibir notificações passivas ao tentar usar ações online enquanto estiver offline (@lnj)</li>
          <li>Automatically reconnect on connection loss (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إعادة الاتصال آلياً عند فقدان الاتصال (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Reconectar automaticamente em caso de perda de conexão (@lnj)</li>
          <li>Contacts page: Display whether online in title (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">صفحة المتصلين: عرض حالة الاتصال في العنوان (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Página de contatos: Exibir se está online no título (@lnj)</li>
          <li>Add different connection error messages (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إضافة رسائل مختلفة لأخطاء الاتصال (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionar mensagens de erro de conexão diferentes (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li>Use QApplication when building with QWidgets (@mart)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">استخدام QApplication عند البناء باستخدام QWidgets (@mart)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Usar QApplication ao construir com QWidgets (@mart)</li>
          <li>Ask user to approve subscription requests (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">طلب موافقة المستخدم على طلبات الاشتراك (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Solicitar ao usuário que aprove os pedidos de assinatura (@lnj)</li>
          <li>Remove contact action: Make JIDs bold (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إجراء إزالة متصل: جعل معرفات JID عريضة (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Remoção de ação de contato: Deixar os JIDs em negrito (@lnj)</li>
          <li>Add contact sheet: Ask for optional message to contact (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">صحيفة إضافة متصل: طلب رسالة اختيارية للمتصل (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionada folha de contato: Solicitar mensagem opcional para contato (@lnj)</li>
          <li>Add empty chat page with help notice to be displayed on start up (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إضافة صفحة دردشة فارغة مع ملاحظة مساعدة لتُعرض عند بدء التشغيل (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionada página de bate-papo vazia com aviso de ajuda a ser exibida na inicialização (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li>Redesign log in page (@sohnybohny)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إعادة تصميم صفحة الولوج (@sohnybohny)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Redesenho da página de login (@sohnybohny)</li>
          <li>Add Copy Invitaion URL action (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إضافة إجراء نسخ رابط الدعوة (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionada ação de copiar URL de convite (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li>Add 'press and hold' functionality for messages context menu (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إضافة وظيفة 'الضغط والاستمرار' للقائمة السياقية للرسائل (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionada funcionalidade de 'pressionar e segurar' ao menu de contexto de mensagens (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li>Add copy to clipboard function for messages (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إضافة وظيفة النسخ إلى الحافظة للرسائل (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionada função de copiar para a área de transferência para mensagens (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li>Add mobile file chooser (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إضافة منتقي ملفات للأجهزة المحمولة (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionado seletor de arquivos para dispositivos móveis (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li>Highlight the currently opened chat on contacts page (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">تمييز الدردشة المفتوحة حالياً في صفحة المتصلين (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Destacar a conversa aberta no momento na página de contatos (@lnj)</li>
          <li>Remove predefined window sizes (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إزالة أحجام النوافذ المحددة مسبقاً (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Removidos tamanhos de janela predefinidos (@lnj)</li>
          <li>Use new Kirigami application header (@nicolasfella)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">استخدام ترويسة تطبيق Kirigami الجديدة (@nicolasfella)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Usar o novo cabeçalho de aplicação Kirigami (@nicolasfella)</li>
          <li>Make images open externally when clicked (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">جعل الصور تُفتح خارجياً عند النقر عليها (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Fazer com que as imagens abram externamente ao clicar (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li>Use QtQuickCompiler (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">استخدام QtQuickCompiler (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Usar QtQuickCompiler (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li>Display upload progress bar (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">عرض شريط تقدم الرفع (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Exibir barra de progresso de upload (@lnj)</li>
          <li>Add text+color avatars as fallback (@lnj, @jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إضافة صور شخصية نصية ملونة كبديل احتياطي (@lnj، @jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionados avatares de texto e cor como alternativa (@lnj, @jbbgameich)</li>
          <li>Remove diaspora log in option (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إزالة خيار ولوج diaspora (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Removida opção de login da diáspora (@lnj)</li>
          <li>Support for Android (@ilyabizyaev)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">دعم أندرويد (@ilyabizyaev)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Suporte para Android (@ilyabizyaev)</li>
          <li>Support for Ubuntu Touch (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">دعم Ubuntu Touch (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Suporte para Ubuntu Touch (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li>Support for MacOS (@ilyabizyaev)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">دعم MacOS (@ilyabizyaev)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Suporte para MacOS (@ilyabizyaev)</li>
          <li>Support for Windows (@ilyabizyaev)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">دعم ويندوز (@ilyabizyaev)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Suporte para Windows (@ilyabizyaev)</li>
          <li>Support for iOS (@ilyabizyaev)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">دعم iOS (@ilyabizyaev)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Suporte para iOS (@ilyabizyaev)</li>
          <li>Add KDE Flatpak (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إضافة حزمة فلات باك كيداي (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionado KDE Flatpak (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li>Switch Android builds to CMake with ECM (@ilyabizyaev)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">تحويل بناء أندرويد إلى CMake مع ECM (@ilyabizyaev)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Alteração das compilações do Android para CMake com ECM (@ilyabizyaev)</li>
          <li>Improve Linux AppImage build script (@ilyabizyaev)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">تحسين سكريبت بناء AppImage للينكس (@ilyabizyaev)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Melhoria do script de compilação do AppImage do Linux (@ilyabizyaev)</li>
          <li>Add additional image formats in AppImage (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إضافة تنسيقات صور إضافية في AppImage (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionados formatos de imagem adicionais no AppImage (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li>Forget passwords on log out (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">نسيان كلمات المرور عند الخروج (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Esquecer senhas ao sair (@lnj)</li>
          <li>Append four random chars to resource (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إلحاق أربعة أحرف عشوائية بالمورد (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionados quatro caracteres aleatórios ao recurso (@lnj)</li>
          <li>Save passwords in base64 instead of clear text (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">حفظ كلمات المرور بتنسيق base64 بدلاً من النص الصريح (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Salvar senhas em base64 em vez de texto simples (@lnj)</li>
          <li>Generate the LICENSE file automatically with all git authors (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">توليد ملف الترخيص آلياً مع كافة مؤلفي git (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Gerar o arquivo LICENSE automaticamente com todos os autores do git (@lnj)</li>
          <li>Store ubuntu touch builds as job artifacts (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">تخزين بناء ubuntu touch كمخرجات مهمة (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Armazenar builds do Ubuntu Touch como artefatos de trabalho (@lnj)</li>
          <li>Add GitLab CI integration (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إضافة تكامل GitLab CI (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionada integração com GitLab CI (@jbbgameich)</li>
        </ul>
        <p>This release fixes the following bugs:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ar">يصلح هذا الإصدار العلل التالية:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca">Aquesta versió soluciona els errors següents:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">Esta versió soluciona els errors següents:</p>
        <p xml:lang="pt-BR">Esta versão corrige os seguintes bugs:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fix blocking of GUI thread while database interaction (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح حظر خيط واجهة المستخدم أثناء التفاعل مع قاعدة البيانات (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Corrigido o bloqueio da thread da GUI durante a interação com o banco de dados (@lnj)</li>
          <li>Fix TLS connection bug (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح علة اتصال TLS (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="he">תוקנה תקלה בחיבור TLS‏ (‎@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Corrigido bug de conexão TLS (@lnj)</li>
          <li>Don't send notifications when receiving own messages via. carbons (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">عدم إرسال تنبيهات عند استلام الرسائل الخاصة عبر كربون الرسائل (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Não enviar notificações ao receber suas próprias mensagens via carbons (@lnj)</li>
          <li>Fix timezone bug of message timestamps (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح علة المنطقة الزمنية للطوابع الزمنية للرسائل (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Corrigido o bug de fuso horário nos registros de data e hora das mensagens (@lnj)</li>
          <li>Fix several message editing bugs (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح عدة علل في تحرير الرسائل (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Corrigidos vários bugs de edição de mensagens (@lnj)</li>
          <li>Fix black icons (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح الأيقونات السوداء (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção de ícones pretos (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li>Fix rich text labels in Plasma Mobile (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاح لصائق النص الغني في بلازما الجوال (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Correção de rótulos de texto formatado no Plasma Mobile (@lnj)</li>
          <li>Small Plasma Mobile fixes (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إصلاحات صغيرة لبلازما الجوال (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Pequenas correções do Plasma Mobile (@jbbgameich)</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release type="stable" version="0.3.2" date="2017-11-25T00:00:00Z">
      <description>
        <p>This release adds the following features:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ar">يضيف هذا الإصدار الميزات التالية:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca">Aquesta versió afegeix les característiques següents:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">Esta versió afig les característiques següents:</p>
        <p xml:lang="pt-BR">Esta versão adiciona as seguintes funcionalidades:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ru">В этом выпуске добавлены следующие возможности:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Added AppImage build script (#138) (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">أُضيف سكريبت بناء AppImage رقم 138 (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionado script de compilação AppImage (#138) (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li>Use relative paths to find resource files (#143) (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">استخدام مسارات نسبية للعثور على ملفات الموارد رقم 143 (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Usar caminhos relativos para encontrar arquivos de recursos (#143) (@lnj)</li>
          <li>Source directory is only used for resource files in debug builds (#146) (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">استخدام دليل المصدر فقط لملفات الموارد في بناءات التنقيح رقم 146 (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">O diretório de origem é usado apenas para arquivos de recursos em builds de depuração (#146) (@lnj)</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release type="stable" version="0.3.1" date="2017-11-20T00:00:00Z">
      <description>
        <p>This release fixes the following bugs:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ar">يصلح هذا الإصدار العلل التالية:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca">Aquesta versió soluciona els errors següents:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">Esta versió soluciona els errors següents:</p>
        <p xml:lang="pt-BR">Esta versão corrige os seguintes bugs:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fixed database creation errors (#135, #132) (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">أُصلحت أخطاء إنشاء قاعدة البيانات رقم 135 و132 (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Erros corrigidos na criação do banco de dados (#135, #132) (@lnj)</li>
          <li>ChatPage: Fixed recipient's instead of author's avatar displayed (#131, #137) (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">صفحة الدردشة: أُصلح عرض صورة المستلم بدلاً من صورة الكاتب رقم 131 و137 (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">ChatPage: Corrigido o problema em que o avatar do destinatário era exibido em vez do avatar do autor (#131, #137) (@lnj)</li>
        </ul>
        <p>This release adds the following features:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ar">يضيف هذا الإصدار الميزات التالية:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca">Aquesta versió afegeix les característiques següents:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">Esta versió afig les característiques següents:</p>
        <p xml:lang="pt-BR">Esta versão adiciona as seguintes funcionalidades:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ru">В этом выпуске добавлены следующие возможности:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Added Travis-CI integration (#133, #134, #136) (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">أُضيف تكامل Travis-CI رقم 133 و134 و136 (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionada integração com Travis-CI (#133, #134, #136) (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li>Added Malay translations (#129) (@MuhdNurHidayat)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">أُضيفت الترجمة الماليزية رقم 129 (@MuhdNurHidayat)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionadas traduções em malaio (#129) (@MuhdNurHidayat)</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release type="stable" version="0.3.0" date="2017-08-15T00:00:00Z">
      <description>
        <p>This release adds the following features:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ar">يضيف هذا الإصدار الميزات التالية:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca">Aquesta versió afegeix les característiques següents:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">Esta versió afig les característiques següents:</p>
        <p xml:lang="pt-BR">Esta versão adiciona as seguintes funcionalidades:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ru">В этом выпуске добавлены следующие возможности:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Added XEP-0280: Message Carbons (#117) (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">أُضيف بروتوكول XEP-0280: كربون الرسائل رقم 117 (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionado XEP-0280: Carbonos de mensagem (#117) (@lnj)</li>
          <li>Added XEP-0054/XEP-0153: VCard-based avatars (#73, #105, #119) (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">أُضيفت الصور الشخصية القائمة على VCard رقم 73 و105 و119 (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionado XEP-0054/XEP-0153: Avatares baseados em VCard (#73, #105, #119) (@lnj)</li>
          <li>Added file storage for simply caching all avatars (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">أُضيف تخزين ملفات لتخبئة كافة الصور الشخصية ببساطة (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionado armazenamento de arquivos para simplesmente guardar em cache todos os avatares (@lnj)</li>
          <li>New roster design - showing round avatars and last message (#118) (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">تصميم جديد لقائمة المتصلين - يعرض صوراً شخصية مستديرة وآخر رسالة رقم 118 (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Novo design da lista de contatos - mostrando avatares redondos e a última mensagem (#118) (@lnj)</li>
          <li>New chat page design - showing time, delivery status and round avatars (#123) (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">تصميم جديد لصفحة الدردشة - يعرض الوقت، وحالة التسليم وصوراً شخصية مستديرة رقم 123 (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Novo design da página de bate-papo - mostrando hora, status de entrega e avatares redondos (#123) (@lnj)</li>
          <li>Switched to XMPP client library "gloox" (#114) (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">الانتقال إلى مكتبة عميل XMPP المسماة "gloox" رقم 114 (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Alteração para a biblioteca cliente XMPP "gloox" (#114) (@lnj)</li>
          <li>Rewritten most of the back-end for gloox and partially also restructured it (#114) (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">أُعيد كتابة معظم الواجهة الخلفية لـ gloox وأُعيدت هيكلتها جزئياً رقم 114 (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Reescrita e reestruturação da maior parte do back-end do Gloox (#114) (@lnj)</li>
          <li>(Re)written new LogHandler for gloox (Swiften had this already included) (#114) (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">أُعيدت كتابة معالج سجلات جديد لـ gloox (كان Swiften يتضمن هذا مسبقاً) رقم 114 (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">(Re)escrita do novo LogHandler para gloox (o Swift já o tinha incluído) (#114) (@lnj)</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release type="stable" version="0.2.3" date="2017-06-19T00:00:00Z">
      <description>
        <p>This release fixes the following bugs:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ar">يصلح هذا الإصدار العلل التالية:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca">Aquesta versió soluciona els errors següents:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">Esta versió soluciona els errors següents:</p>
        <p xml:lang="pt-BR">Esta versão corrige os seguintes bugs:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>LoginPage: Remove material shadow (#113) (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">صفحة الولوج: إزالة ظل المادة رقم 113 (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Página de login: Remover sombra do material (#113) (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li>Kaidan was crashing since v0.2.2 when inserting a new message to the DB (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">كان كيدان ينهار منذ الإصدار 0.2.2 عند إدراج رسالة جديدة في قاعدة البيانات (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">O Kaidan estava travando desde a versão 0.2.2 ao inserir uma nova mensagem no banco de dados (@lnj)</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release type="stable" version="0.2.2" date="2017-06-19T00:00:00Z">
      <description>
        <p>This release fixes the following bug:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ar">يصلح هذا الإصدار العلة التالية:</p>
        <p xml:lang="pt-BR">Esta versão corrige o seguinte bug:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>RosterPage: Clear TextFields after closing AddContactSheet (#106) (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">صفحة قائمة المتصلين: مسح حقول النص بعد إغلاق صحيفة إضافة متصل رقم 106 (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">RosterPage: Limpar campos de texto após fechar AddContactSheet (#106) (@jbbgameich)</li>
        </ul>
        <p>This release adds the following features:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ar">يضيف هذا الإصدار الميزات التالية:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca">Aquesta versió afegeix les característiques següents:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">Esta versió afig les característiques següents:</p>
        <p xml:lang="pt-BR">Esta versão adiciona as seguintes funcionalidades:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ru">В этом выпуске добавлены следующие возможности:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>RosterController: Save lastMessage for each contact (#108) (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">تحكم قائمة المتصلين: حفظ آخر رسالة لكل متصل رقم 108 (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">RosterController: Salvar última mensagem para cada contato (#108) (@lnj)</li>
          <li>Add database versioning and conversion (#110) (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إضافة إصدارات قاعدة البيانات وتحويلها رقم 110 (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionado versionamento e conversão de banco de dados (#110) (@lnj)</li>
          <li>Database: Add new roster row `avatarHash` (#112) (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">قاعدة البيانات: إضافة صف جديد لقائمة المتصلين `avatarHash` رقم 112 (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Banco de dados: Adicionada nova linha de lista `avatarHash` (#112) (@lnj)</li>
          <li>CMake: Add feature summary (#109) (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">CMake: إضافة ملخص الميزات رقم 109 (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">CMake: Adicionado resumo de recursos (#109) (@lnj)</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release type="stable" version="0.2.1" date="2017-06-08T00:00:00Z">
      <description>
        <p>This release fixes the following bug:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ar">يصلح هذا الإصدار العلة التالية:</p>
        <p xml:lang="pt-BR">Esta versão corrige o seguinte bug:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Roster page: Fixed style: Now has contour lines and a cool material effect (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">صفحة قائمة المتصلين: أُصلح النمط: لديها الآن خطوط كنتورية وتأثير مادة رائع (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Página de lista: Estilo corrigido: Agora possui linhas de contorno e um efeito de material bacana (@lnj)</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release type="stable" version="0.2.0" date="2017-06-06T00:00:00Z">
      <description>
        <p>This release adds the following features:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ar">يضيف هذا الإصدار الميزات التالية:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca">Aquesta versió afegeix les característiques següents:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">Esta versió afig les característiques següents:</p>
        <p xml:lang="pt-BR">Esta versão adiciona as seguintes funcionalidades:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ru">В этом выпуске добавлены следующие возможности:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Add Roster Editing (#84, #86) (@lnj, @jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إضافة تحرير قائمة المتصلين رقم 84 و86 (@lnj، @jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionada edição de lista (#84, #86) (@lnj, @jbbgameich)</li>
          <li>Roster refreshes now automatically (#83) (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">قائمة المتصلين تُحدث الآن آلياً رقم 83 (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">A lista agora é atualizada automaticamente (#83) (@lnj)</li>
          <li>Contacts are now sorted (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">المتصلون مفروزون الآن (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Os contatos são ordenados (@lnj)</li>
          <li>Add unread message counters (#92, #101) (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إضافة عدادات الرسائل غير المقروءة رقم 92 و101 (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionados contadores de mensagens não lidas (#92, #101) (@lnj)</li>
          <li>Add LibNotify-Linux notifications (#90) (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إضافة تنبيهات LibNotify للينكس رقم 90 (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionadas notificações LibNotify-Linux (#90) (@lnj)</li>
          <li>Add custom JID resources (#82) (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إضافة موارد JID مخصصة رقم 82 (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionados recursos JID personalizados (#82) (@lnj)</li>
          <li>Add XEP-0184: Message Delivery Receipts (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">إضافة XEP-0184: Message Delivery Receipts (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Adicionado XEP-0184: Recibos de entrega de mensagens (@lnj)</li>
          <li>Disable stream compression by default (for HipChat/other server compatibility) (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">تعطيل ضغط الدفق مبدئياً (للتوافق مع HipChat والخواديم الأخرى) (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Desativada a compressão de fluxo por padrão (para compatibilidade com HipChat/outros servidores)</li>
          <li>GUI: Port to Kirigami 2 (#81) (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">واجهة المستخدم: النقل إلى Kirigami 2 رقم 81 (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="he">ממשק משתמש: הסבה ל־Kirigami 2‏ (#81) (‎@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">GUI: Porte para o Kirigami 2 (#81) (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li>User Material/Green Theme per default (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">استخدام سمة المادة/الخضراء مبدئياً (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Tema Material/Verde do usuário por padrão (@lnj)</li>
          <li>Login page: New design with diaspora* login option (#87) (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">صفحة الولوج: تصميم جديد مع خيار ولوج diaspora* رقم 87 (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Página de login: Novo design com opção de login da diáspora* (#87) (@jbbgameich)</li>
          <li>Chat page: Slightly improved design (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">صفحة الدردشة: تحسين التصميم قليلاً (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="he">עמוד שיחה: שיפור קל בעיצוב (‎@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Página de bate-papo: Design ligeiramente melhorado (@lnj)</li>
        </ul>
        <p>This release fixes the following bugs:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ar">يصلح هذا الإصدار العلل التالية:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca">Aquesta versió soluciona els errors següents:</p>
        <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">Esta versió soluciona els errors següents:</p>
        <p xml:lang="pt-BR">Esta versão corrige os seguintes bugs:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>AboutPage: Fix possible closing of multiple pages (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="ar">صفحة "عن": إصلاح إمكانية إغلاق صفحات متعددة (@lnj)</li>
          <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Página Sobre: Corrigido possível fechamento de várias páginas (@lnj)</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1">
    <content_attribute id="social-chat">intense</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="social-audio">intense</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="social-location">intense</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="social-contacts">intense</content_attribute>
  </content_rating>
</component>
