<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>im.kaidan.kaidan</id>
  <name>Kaidan</name>
  <name xml:lang="ar">كايدان</name>
  <name xml:lang="ca">Kaidan</name>
  <name xml:lang="ca-valencia">Kaidan</name>
  <name xml:lang="cs">Kaidan</name>
  <name xml:lang="de">Kaidan</name>
  <name xml:lang="el">Kaidan</name>
  <name xml:lang="en-GB">Kaidan</name>
  <name xml:lang="eo">Kaidan</name>
  <name xml:lang="es">Kaidan</name>
  <name xml:lang="eu">Kaidan</name>
  <name xml:lang="fi">Kaidan</name>
  <name xml:lang="fr">Kaidan</name>
  <name xml:lang="gl">Kaidan</name>
  <name xml:lang="hi">कैदान</name>
  <name xml:lang="id">Kaidan</name>
  <name xml:lang="ie">Kaidan</name>
  <name xml:lang="it">Kaidan</name>
  <name xml:lang="ka">Kaidan</name>
  <name xml:lang="ko">Kaidan</name>
  <name xml:lang="nl">Kaidan</name>
  <name xml:lang="nn">Kaidan</name>
  <name xml:lang="pl">Kaidan</name>
  <name xml:lang="pt">Kaidan</name>
  <name xml:lang="pt-BR">Kaidan</name>
  <name xml:lang="sk">Kaidan</name>
  <name xml:lang="sl">Kaidan</name>
  <name xml:lang="sv">Kaidan</name>
  <name xml:lang="tr">Kaidan</name>
  <name xml:lang="uk">Kaidan</name>
  <name xml:lang="x-test">xxKaidanxx</name>
  <name xml:lang="zh-CN">Kaidan</name>
  <name xml:lang="zh-TW">Kaidan</name>
  <summary>Modern chat app for every device</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ar">تطبيق دردشة حديث لكل جهاز</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ca">Aplicació moderna de xat per a tots els dispositius</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ca-valencia">Aplicació moderna de xat per a tots els dispositius</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="cs">Moderní klient pro rozhovory pro každé zařízení</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="en-GB">Modern chat app for every device</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="eo">Moderna retbabililo por ĉiu aparato</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="es">Aplicación de chat moderna para todos los dispositivos</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="fr">Application moderne de messagerie instantanée sur n'importe quel périphérique</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="gl">Aplicación de charla moderna para calquera dispositivo.</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="id">Aplikasi chat modern untuk setiap peranti</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="it">Programma di chat moderno per qualsiasi dispositivo</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ko">모든 장치에서 사용할 수 있는 현대적인 채팅 앱</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="nl">Moderne chat-toepassing voor elk apparaat</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="nn">Moderne nettprat-program for alle typar einingar</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pl">Nowoczesna aplikacja do rozmów na każde urządzenie</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sl">Moderna aplikacija za klepet za vsako napravo</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sv">Modernt chattprogram för alla enheter</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="tr">Her aygıt için çağdaş sohbet uygulaması</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="uk">Сучасна програма для спілкування на будь-якому пристрої</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="x-test">xxModern chat app for every devicexx</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="zh-CN">适用于各种设备的现代聊天应用</summary>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0+</project_license>
  <description>
    <p>Kaidan is a user-friendly and modern chat app for every device. It uses the open communication protocol XMPP (Jabber). Unlike other chat apps, you are not dependent on one specific service provider.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ar">كايدان هو تطبيق دردشة حديث وسهل الاستخدام لكل الأجهزة. يستخدم بروتوكول الاتصالات المفتوح XMPP (Jabber). على عكس تطبيقات الدردشة الأخرى، لا تعتمد على مزود خدمة محدد.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca">El Kaidan és una aplicació de xat fàcil d'emprar i moderna per a tots els dispositius. Fa servir el protocol obert de comunicacions XMPP (Jabber). A diferència d'altres aplicacions de xat, no dependreu d'un proveïdor de serveis en concret.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">Kaidan és una aplicació de xat fàcil d'emprar i moderna per a tots els dispositius. Utilitza el protocol obert de comunicacions XMPP (Jabber). A diferència d'altres aplicacions de xat, no dependreu d'un proveïdor de serveis en concret.</p>
    <p xml:lang="en-GB">Kaidan is a user-friendly and modern chat app for every device. It uses the open communication protocol XMPP (Jabber). Unlike other chat apps, you are not dependent on one specific service provider.</p>
    <p xml:lang="eo">Kaidan estas uzebla kaj moderna babilejo por ĉiu aparato. Ĝi uzas la malferman komunikan protokolon XMPP (Jabber). Male al aliaj babilaj apoj, vi ne dependas de unu specifa servoprovizanto.</p>
    <p xml:lang="es">Kaidan es una aplicación de chat moderna y fácil de usar para todos los dispositivos. Usa el protocolo de comunicación abierto XMPP (Jabber). A diferencia de otras aplicaciones de chat, no depende de un proveedor de servicios específico.</p>
    <p xml:lang="fi">Kaidan on joka laitteen käyttäjäystävällinen ja nykyaikainen keskustelusovellus. Se käyttää avointa XMPP-viestintäyhteyskäytäntöä (Jabber). Toisin kuin muissa keskustelusovelluksissa, et ole riippuvainen tietystä palveluntarjoajasta.</p>
    <p xml:lang="fr">Kaidan est une application moderne et conviviale de messagerie instantanée pour n'importe quel périphérique. Il utilise le protocole de communication libre « XMPP » (Jabber). Contrairement aux autres applications de messagerie instantanée, vous n'êtes dépendant d'aucun fournisseur de services spécifiques.</p>
    <p xml:lang="gl">Kaidan é unha aplicación de charla moderna e amigábel para cada dispositivo. Usa o protocolo aberto de comunicacións XMPP (Jabber). Ao contrario que outras apps, non dependes dun provedor de servizos específico.</p>
    <p xml:lang="id">Kaidan adalah aplikasi chating yang mudah digunakan dan modern untuk setiap peranti. Aplikasi ini menggunakan protokol komunikasi terbuka XMPP (Jabber). Tidak seperti aplikasi chating lainnya, Anda tidak bergantung pada satu penyedia layanan tertentu.</p>
    <p xml:lang="it">Kaidan è un programma di chat amichevole e moderno per qualsiasi dispositivo. Utilizza il protocollo di comunicazione aperto XMPP (Jabber). A differenza di altri programmi non sei dipendente da uno specifico fornitore di servizi.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ka">Kaidan არის მოსახერხებელი და თანამედროვე ჩეთის აპლიკაციაა ყველა მოწყობილობისთვის. ის იყენებს ღია საკომუნიკაციო პროტოკოლს XMPP (Jabber). სხვა ჩეთის აპებისგან განსხვავებით, თქვენ არ ხართ დამოკიდებული ერთ კონკრეტულ სერვისის პროვაიდერზე.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ko">Kaidan은 모든 장치에서 사용할 수 있는 사용자 편의적인 채팅 앱입니다. 개방형 통신 프로토콜 XMPP(Jabber)를 사용합니다. 다른 채팅 앱과는 다르게 하나의 서비스 공급자에 의존하지 않습니다.</p>
    <p xml:lang="nl">Kaidan is een gebruikersvriendelijke en moderne chat-toepassing voor elk apparaat. Het gebruikt het open communicatieprotocol XMPP (Jabber). Anders dan andere chat-toepassingen bent u niet afhankelijk van één specifieke serviceprovider.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pl">Kaidan to przyjazna użytkownikom i nowoczesna aplikacja do rozmów na każdym urządzeniu. Używa otwartego protokołu porozumiewania się o nazwie XMPP (Jabber). W odróżnieniu od innych aplikacji do rozmów, nie jesteś zależny od jednego dostawcy tej usługi.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt">O Kaidan é uma aplicação de conversas amigável e moderna para todos os tipos de dispositivos. Usa o protocolo aberto de comunicações XMPP (Jabber). Ao contrário das outras aplicações de conversas, não está dependente de um fornecedor de serviços específico.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sl">Kaidan je uporabniku prijazna in moderna aplikacija za klepet na vsaki napravi. Uporablja odprti komunikacijski protokol XMPP (Jabber). Za razliko od drugih aplikacij za klepet, niste odvisni od enega samega ponudnika storitev.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sv">Kaidan är ett användarvänligt och modernt chattprogram för alla enheter. Det använder det öppna kommunikationsprotokollet XMPP (Jabber). I motsats till andra chattprogram är du inte beroende av en specific tjänstleverantör.</p>
    <p xml:lang="tr">Kaidan, her tür aygıt için kullanıcı dostu ve çağdaş teknolojilerle yaratılmış bir sohbet uygulamasıdır. Açık bir sohbet protokolü olan XMPP’yi (Jabber) kullanır. Diğer sohbet uygulamalarının aksine, belirli bir hizmet sağlayıcıya bağlı kalmazsınız.</p>
    <p xml:lang="uk">Kaidan — зручна для користування та сучасна програма для спілкування на будь-якому пристрої. У ній використано відкрити протокол для спілкування XMPP (Jabber). На відміну від інших програм для спілкування, ви не залежатимете від одного певного надавача послуг зв'язку.</p>
    <p xml:lang="x-test">xxKaidan is a user-friendly and modern chat app for every device. It uses the open communication protocol XMPP (Jabber). Unlike other chat apps, you are not dependent on one specific service provider.xx</p>
    <p xml:lang="zh-CN">Kaidan 是用户友好、现代的聊天应用，适用于各种设备。它使用开放通信协议 XMPP（Jabber）。与其他聊天应用不同，您不依赖于某个特定的服务提供者。</p>
    <p xml:lang="zh-TW">Kaidan 是一個友善且現代化的聊天應用程式，且支援任何裝置。它使用 XMPP (Jabber)，一個開放的通訊協定。如此，您不需依賴任何一個特定的服務提供者。</p>
    <p>Kaidan does not have all basic features yet and has still some stability issues. But we do our best to improve it!</p>
    <p xml:lang="ar">لا يحتوي كايدان على جميع الميزات الأساسية حتى الآن ولا يزال يعاني من بعض مشكلات الاستقرار. لكننا نبذل قصارى جهدنا لتحسينه!</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca">El Kaidan encara no té totes les característiques bàsiques i té alguns problemes d'estabilitat. Però fem tot el possible per a millorar-ho!</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">Kaidan encara no té totes les característiques bàsiques i té alguns problemes d'estabilitat. Però fem tot el possible per a millorar-ho!</p>
    <p xml:lang="en-GB">Kaidan does not have all basic features yet and has still some stability issues. But we do our best to improve it!</p>
    <p xml:lang="eo">Kaidan ankoraŭ ne havas ĉiujn bazajn funkciojn kaj ankoraŭ havas kelkajn stabilecajn problemojn. Sed ni faras nian eblon por plibonigi ĝin!</p>
    <p xml:lang="es">Kaidan aún no posee todas las funciones básicas y todavía tiene algunos problemas de estabilidad. ¡Pero hacemos todo lo posible para mejorarlo!</p>
    <p xml:lang="fi">Kaidanissa ei vielä ole kaikkia perusominaisuuksia, ja siinä on joitakin vakausongelmia. Mutta teemme parhaamme parantaaksemme sitä!</p>
    <p xml:lang="fr">Kaidan ne possède pas encore toutes les fonctionnalités de base et présente encore quelques problèmes de stabilité. Mais tout est fait de notre côté pour l'améliorer !</p>
    <p xml:lang="gl">Kaidan aínda non inclúe todas as características básicas  e ten algún problema de estabilidade. Pero traballamos moito para mellorala!</p>
    <p xml:lang="id">Kaidan belum memiliki semua fitur dasar dan masih memiliki beberapa masalah stabilitas. Namun, kami berusaha sebaik mungkin untuk memperbaikinya!</p>
    <p xml:lang="it">Kaidan non ha ancora tutte le funzionalità di base e ha qualche problema di stabilità, ma stiamo facendo del nostro meglio per migliorarlo.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ka">Kaidan-ს ჯერ არ აქვს ყველა ძირითადი თვისება და ჯერ კიდევ აქვს სტაბილურობის პრობლემები. მაგრამ ჩვენ ყველაფერს ვაკეთებთ მის გასაუმჯობესებლად!</p>
    <p xml:lang="ko">Kaidan에는 아직 빠져 있는 기본 기능이 있으며 완벽히 안정적이지는 않습니다. 최선을 다해서 개선하고 있습니다!</p>
    <p xml:lang="nl">Kaidan heeft no niet alle basisfuncties en er zijn nog steeds enige stabiliteitsproblemen. Maar we doen ons best om het te verbeteren!</p>
    <p xml:lang="pl">Kaidan nadal nie zapewnia wszystkich podstawowych możliwości i ma pewne kłopoty ze stabilnością. Mimo tego robimy wszystko, co możemy, aby zmienić ten stan na lepszy!</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt">O Kaidan ainda não tem todas as funcionalidades básicas, e tem à mesma algumas questões de estabilidade. Mas estamos a dar o nosso melhor para a aperfeiçoar!</p>
    <p xml:lang="sl">Kaidan še nima vseh osnovnih zmožnosti in ima še vedno nekaj težav s stabilnostjo. A se trudimo po najboljših močeh za izboljšave!</p>
    <p xml:lang="sv">Kaidan har inte alla grundfunktioner ännu och har fortfarande vissa stabilitetsproblem. Men vi gör vårt bästa för att förbättra det!</p>
    <p xml:lang="tr">Kaidan henüz kimi temel özellikleri desteklemez ve kararlılık sorunları olabilir. Ancak onu iyileştirmek için elimizden gelenin en iyisini yapıyoruz!</p>
    <p xml:lang="uk">У Kaidan поки немає усіх базових можливостей і є певні проблеми зі стабільністю. Але ми не припиняємо удосконалювати програму!</p>
    <p xml:lang="x-test">xxKaidan does not have all basic features yet and has still some stability issues. But we do our best to improve it!xx</p>
    <p xml:lang="zh-CN">Kaidan 尚未具备所有基本功能，仍然存在某些稳定性问题。但我们会尽最大努力改善它！</p>
    <p xml:lang="zh-TW">Kaidan 尚未支援所有基礎功能，並且仍有一些穩定性問題。但我們正努力改善它！</p>
  </description>
  <developer id="org.kde">
    <name>KDE</name>
  </developer>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">im.kaidan.kaidan.desktop</launchable>
  <url type="homepage">https://kaidan.im</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://invent.kde.org/network/kaidan/-/issues</url>
  <url type="help">https://invent.kde.org/network/kaidan/-/wikis/home</url>
  <url type="translate">https://l10n.kde.org/stats/gui/trunk-kf5/package/kaidan/</url>
  <url type="vcs-browser">https://invent.kde.org/network/kaidan</url>
  <categories>
    <category>Network</category>
  </categories>
  <provides>
    <binary>kaidan</binary>
  </provides>
  <translation type="qt">KDE Localization</translation>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <caption>Chat on a desktop and mobile device</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ar">الدردشة على سطح المكتب والجهاز المحمول</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ca">Xat en un escriptori i en un dispositiu mòbil</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ca-valencia">Xat en un escriptori i en un dispositiu mòbil</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="en-GB">Chat on a desktop and mobile device</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="eo">Retbabilu sur labortablaj kaj porteblaj aparatoj</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="es">Chat en un escritorio y en un dispositivo móvil</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="fi">Viestittele työpöydällä ja mobiililaitteella</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="fr">Messagerie instantanée sur ordinateur de bureau et sur périphérique mobile.</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="gl">Charla nun dispositivo móbil ou no escritorio.</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="id">Chat di desktop dan peranti ponsel</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="it">Chat su un dispositivo desktop e su uno mobile</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ka">ჩატი კომპიუტერზე და მობილურზე</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ko">데스크톱과 모바일 장치에서 대화</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="nl">Chat op een bureaublad en op een mobiel apparaat</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="nn">Nettprat på PC og på mobil eining</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pl">Rozmawiaj na urządzeniu biurkowym i przenośnym</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pt">Conversa num computador e num dispositivo móvel</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sl">Klepet na namizju in na mobilni napravi</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sv">Chatt på ett skrivbord och på en mobil</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="tr">Masaüstü ve taşınabilir bir aygıtta sohbet</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="uk">Спілкування на комп'ютері та на мобільному пристрої</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="x-test">xxChat on a desktop and mobile devicexx</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="zh-CN">在桌面和移动设备上聊天</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="zh-TW">在桌面與行動裝置上聊天</caption>
      <image type="source">https://www.kaidan.im/images/screenshot.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <releases>
    <release type="stable" version="0.10.1" date="2024-12-14T00:00:00Z">
      <description>
        <p>This release fixes the following bugs:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fix displaying files of each message in appropriate message bubble (melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix sending fallback messages for clients not supporting XEP-0447: Stateless file sharing (melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix margins within message bubbles (melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix hiding hidden message part (melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix displaying marker for new messages (melvo)</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release type="stable" version="0.10.0" date="2024-12-09T00:00:00Z">
      <description>
        <p>This release adds the following features:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Add server address completion (fazevedo)</li>
          <li>Allow to edit account's profile (jbb)</li>
          <li>Store and display delivery states of message reactions (melvo)</li>
          <li>Send pending message reactions after going online (melvo)</li>
          <li>Enable user to resend a message reaction if it previously failed (melvo)</li>
          <li>Open contact addition as page (mobile) or dialog (desktop) (melvo)</li>
          <li>Add option to open chat if contact exists on adding contact (melvo)</li>
          <li>Use consistent page with search bar for searching its content (melvo)</li>
          <li>Add local message removal (taibsu)</li>
          <li>Allow reacting to own messages (melvo)</li>
          <li>Add login option to chat (melvo)</li>
          <li>Display day of the week or "yesterday" for last messages (taibsu, melvo)</li>
          <li>Add media overview (fazevedo, melvo)</li>
          <li>Add contact list filtering by account and labels (i.e., roster groups) (incl. addition/removal) (melvo, tech-bash)</li>
          <li>Add message date sections to chat (melvo)</li>
          <li>Add support for automatic media downloads (fazevedo)</li>
          <li>Add filtering contacts by availability (melvo)</li>
          <li>Add item to contact list on first received direct message (melvo)</li>
          <li>Add support for blocking chat addresses (lnj)</li>
          <li>Improve notes chat (chat with oneself) usage (melvo)</li>
          <li>Place avatar above chat address and name in account/contact details on narrow window (melvo)</li>
          <li>Reload camera device for QR code scanning as soon as it is plugged in / enabled (melvo)</li>
          <li>Provide slider for QR code scanning to adjust camera zoom (melvo)</li>
          <li>Add contact to contact list on receiving presence subscription request (melvo)</li>
          <li>Add encryption key authentication via entering key IDs (melvo)</li>
          <li>Improve connecting to server and authentication (XEP-0388: Extensible SASL Profile (SASL 2), XEP-0386: Bind 2, XEP-0484: Fast Authentication Streamlining Tokens, XEP-0368: SRV records for XMPP over TLS) (lnj)</li>
          <li>Support media sharing with more clients even for sharing multiple files at once (XEP-0447: Stateless file sharing v0.3) (lnj)</li>
          <li>Display and check media upload size limit (fazevedo)</li>
          <li>Redesign message input field to use rounded corners and resized/symbolic buttons (melvo)</li>
          <li>Add support for moving account data to another account, informing contacts and restoring settings for moved contacts (XEP-0283: Moved) (fazevedo)</li>
          <li>Add group chat support with invitations, user listing, participant mentioning and private/public group chat filtering (XEP-0369: Mediated Information eXchange (MIX), XEP-0405: Mediated Information eXchange (MIX): Participant Server Requirements, XEP-0406: Mediated Information eXchange (MIX): MIX Administration, XEP-0407: Mediated Information eXchange (MIX): Miscellaneous Capabilities) (melvo)</li>
          <li>Add button to cancel message correction (melvo)</li>
          <li>Display marker for new messages (melvo)</li>
          <li>Add enhanced account-wide and per contact notification settings depending on group chat mentions and presence (melvo)</li>
          <li>Focus input fields appropriately (melvo)</li>
          <li>Add support for replying to messages (XEP-0461: Message Replies) (melvo)</li>
          <li>Indicate that Kaidan is busy during account deletion and group chat actions (melvo)</li>
          <li>Hide account deletion button if In-Band Registration is not supported (melvo)</li>
          <li>Embed login area in page for QR code scanning and page for web registration instead of opening start page (melvo)</li>
          <li>Redesign onboarding user interface including new page for choosing provider to create account on (melvo)</li>
          <li>Handle various corner cases that can occur during account creation (melvo)</li>
          <li>Update to XMPP Providers v2 (melvo)</li>
          <li>Hide voice message button if uploading is not supported (melvo)</li>
          <li>Replace custom images for message delivery states with regular theme icons (melvo)</li>
          <li>Free up message content space by hiding unneeded avatars and increasing maximum message bubble width (melvo)</li>
          <li>Highlight draft message text to easily see what is not sent yet (melvo)</li>
          <li>Store sent media in suitable directories with appropriate file extensions (melvo)</li>
          <li>Allow sending media with less steps from recording to sending (melvo)</li>
          <li>Add media to be sent in scrollable area above message input field (melvo)</li>
          <li>Display original images (if available) as previews instead of their thumbnails (melvo)</li>
          <li>Display high resolution thumbnails for locally stored videos as previews instead of their thumbnails (melvo)</li>
          <li>Send smaller thumbnails (melvo)</li>
          <li>Show camera status and reload camera once plugged in for taking pictures or recording videos (melvo)</li>
          <li>Add zoom slider for taking pictures or recording videos (melvo)</li>
          <li>Show overlay with description when files are dragged to be dropped on chats for being shared (melvo)</li>
          <li>Show location previews on a map (melvo)</li>
          <li>Open locations in user-defined way (system default, in-app, web) (melvo)</li>
          <li>Delete media that is only captured for sending but not sent (melvo)</li>
          <li>Add voice message recorder to message input field (melvo)</li>
          <li>Add inline audio player (melvo)</li>
          <li>Add context menu entry for opening directory of media files (melvo)</li>
          <li>Show collapsible buttons to send media/locations inside of message input field (melvo)</li>
          <li>Move button for adding hidden message part to new collapsible button area (melvo)</li>
        </ul>
        <p>This release fixes the following bugs:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fix index out of range error in message search (taibsu)</li>
          <li>Fix updating last message information in contact list (melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix multiple corrections of the same message (melvo, taibsu)</li>
          <li>Request delivery receipts for pending messages (melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix sorting roster items (melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix displaying spoiler messages (melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix displaying errors and encryption warnings for messages (melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix fetching messages from server's archive (melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix various encryption problems (melvo)</li>
          <li>Send delivery receipts for catched up messages (melvo)</li>
          <li>Do not hide last message date if contact name is too long (melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix displaying emojis (melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix several OMEMO bugs (melvo)</li>
          <li>Remove all locally stored data related to removed accounts (melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix displaying media preview file names/sizes (melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix disconnecting from server when application window is closed including timeout on connection problems (melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix media/location sharing (melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix handling emoji message reactions (melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix moving pinned chats (fazevedo)</li>
          <li>Fix drag and drop for files and pasting them (melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix sending/displaying media in selected order (lnj, melvo)</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Kaidan is REUSE-compliant now</p>
        <p>Kaidan requires Qt 5.15 and QXmpp 1.9 now</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release type="stable" version="0.9.2" date="2024-07-24T00:00:00Z">
      <description>
        <p>This release fixes the following bugs:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fix file extension for downloads when mime type is empty (lnj)</li>
          <li>Fix file downloads without a source URL could be started (lnj)</li>
          <li>Fix file messages are never marked as sent (lnj)</li>
          <li>Fix message body of previous file selection was used (lnj)</li>
          <li>Fix missing receipt request (for green checkmark) on media messages (lnj)</li>
          <li>Fix outgoing encrypted media messages are displayed as unencrypted (lnj)</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release type="stable" version="0.9.1" date="2023-05-07T00:00:00Z"/>
    <release type="stable" version="0.9.0" date="2023-04-30T00:00:00Z">
      <description>
        <p>This release adds the following features:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>New message bubble design based on Tok's code (lnj)</li>
          <li>Group messages from same author (lnj)</li>
          <li>Introduce machine-readable DOAP file describing Kaidan's XMPP compliance (melvo)</li>
          <li>New chat background picture (raghu)</li>
          <li>OMEMO 2 support with easy trust management (melvo)</li>
          <li>Read markers (melvo)</li>
          <li>The chat page title can be clicked to open the user's profile now (mbb)</li>
          <li>Support file sharing with multiple files per message, thumbnails and end-to-end encryption (lnj, jbb)</li>
          <li>Restore window position on start (melvo)</li>
          <li>Chat pinning (melvo, tech-bash)</li>
          <li>Emoji message reactions (melvo)</li>
          <li>The message search now also works with messages that are not displayed (taibsu)</li>
          <li>Public group chat search (without group chat support yet) (fazevedo)</li>
          <li>Account settings with ability to change avatar and profile information (taibsu)</li>
          <li>Redesign of settings, redesign of user profiles as sheet instead of page (mbb)</li>
          <li>Store message drafts locally (fazevedo)</li>
        </ul>
        <p>We switched from Weblate to the KDE translation system</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release type="stable" version="0.8.0" date="2021-05-28T00:00:00Z">
      <description>
        <p>This release adds the following features:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Add typing notifications (XEP-0085: Chat State Notifications) (jbb)</li>
          <li>Add message history syncing (XEP-0313: Message Archive Management) (lnj)</li>
          <li>Window size is restored (melvo)</li>
          <li>The server's website link is displayed if account creation is disabled (melvo)</li>
          <li>Use breeze theme on macOS (jbb)</li>
          <li>Improved user strings &amp; descriptions (melvo)</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release type="stable" version="0.7.0" date="2021-02-02T00:00:00Z">
      <description>
        <p>This release adds the following features:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Display client information (name, version, OS) of contacts (jbb, lnj)</li>
          <li>Drag'n'drop for sending files (jbb)</li>
          <li>Allow pasting images from the clipboard (Ctrl+Shift+V) into the chat (jbb)</li>
          <li>Allow inserting newlines using Shift+Enter (jbb)</li>
          <li>Add configuration of custom hostname/port (jbb, melvo)</li>
          <li>Favourite emojis are shown by default now (melvo)</li>
          <li>Search emojis by ":&lt;name&gt;" (melvo)</li>
          <li>Display connection errors in the global drawer after login (melvo)</li>
          <li>Improved design of media preview sheets (jbb)</li>
          <li>Restructure message sending bar (melvo)</li>
        </ul>
        <p>This release fixes the following bugs:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Do not interpret random URLs as files anymore (lnj)</li>
          <li>Fix the style of buttons when using Material style (melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix file dialog and media drawer opening in some cases (melvo)</li>
          <li>Fix opening of the LoginPage when scanning QR code without password (melvo)</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Kaidan requires Qt 5.14 now</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release type="stable" version="0.6.0" date="2020-08-20T00:00:00Z">
      <description>
        <p>This release adds the following features:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>When offline, messages are cached now to be sent later (yugubich)</li>
          <li>It's allowed to also correct other messages than the last one now (yugubich)</li>
          <li>Also pending (unsent) messages can be corrected now (yugubich)</li>
          <li>Chats can be opened from the notifications now (melvo, jbb, cacahueto)</li>
          <li>New option to permanently hide your password in Kaidan (melvo)</li>
          <li>New buttons for easily copying your jid and password (jbb, fazevedo)</li>
          <li>Moved account management pages into the settings (jbb)</li>
          <li>The cursor is moved to the end of the text field when correcting a message now (melvo)</li>
          <li>Scanning QR codes without a password works now and results in only the JID being set (melvo)</li>
          <li>The roster is called contact list now (jbb)</li>
          <li>The resource for the displayed presence is picked with fixed rules now (it was random before which resource is displayed) (lnj)</li>
          <li>Handle notifications differently on GNOME to keep them in the notifications area (melvo)</li>
          <li>Switched to the upstream HTTP File Upload implementation (lnj)</li>
          <li>Code refactoring and partial rewrite of the following classes: Kaidan, ClientWorker, RosterManager, PresenceCache, DownloadManager, TransferCache, QrCodeDecoder (lnj, jbb)</li>
        </ul>
        <p>This release fixes the following bugs:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Playback issues in media video preview (fazevedo)</li>
          <li>Messages sent from other of your devices are displayed as they were sent by the chat partner (lnj)</li>
          <li>Notifications are shown persistently on the screen (jbb)</li>
          <li>Roster names are not updated in the database (melvo)</li>
          <li>Roster items are not updated in the model correctly (melvo)</li>
          <li>All sheets contain two headers: It uses the new built-in header property now (jbb)</li>
          <li>Unreadable buttons with white text on withe background in some styles (jbb)</li>
          <li>Database version isn't saved correctly (melvo)</li>
          <li>Errors when building with newer ZXing versions (vkrause)</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Kaidan requires a C++17-compliant compiler now</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release type="stable" version="0.5.0" date="2020-04-04T00:00:00Z">
      <description>
        <p>This release adds the following features:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Add parsing of XMPP URIs (lnj, melvo)</li>
          <li>Add QR code scanning and generation (lnj, jbb, melvo)</li>
          <li>Add contact search (zatrox, lnj)</li>
          <li>Add muting notifications for messages of contacts (zatrox)</li>
          <li>Add renaming contacts (lnj, zatrox, melvo)</li>
          <li>Show user profile information (lnj, jbb)</li>
          <li>Add extended multimedia support (fazevedo)</li>
          <li>Add message search (blue)</li>
          <li>Redesign contact list, text avatar, counter for unread messages, chat page, chat message bubble (melvo)</li>
          <li>Show notifications on Android (melvo, jbb, cacahueto)</li>
          <li>Add option for enabling or disabling an account temporarily (melvo)</li>
          <li>Refactor login screen with hints for invalid credentials and better usage of keyboard keys (melvo)</li>
          <li>Add message quoting (jbb)</li>
          <li>Truncate very long messages to avoid crashing Kaidan or using it to full capacity (jbb)</li>
          <li>Add button with link for issue tracking to about page (melvo)</li>
          <li>Improve messages for connection errors (melvo)</li>
          <li>Add account deletion (melvo, mbb)</li>
          <li>Redesign logo and global drawer banner (melvo, mbb)</li>
          <li>Add onboarding with registration, normal login and QR code login (melvo, lnj, jbb, mbb)</li>
          <li>Add OARS rating (nickrichards)</li>
          <li>Add secondary roster sorting by contact name (lnj)</li>
          <li>Add support for recording audio and video messages (fazevedo)</li>
          <li>Add Kaidan to KDE's F-Droid repository (nicolasfella)</li>
          <li>Improve build scripts for better cross-platform support (jbb, cacahueto, lnj, mauro)</li>
          <li>Refactor code for better performance and stability (lnj, jbb, melvo)</li>
          <li>Add documentation to achieve easier maintenance (melvo, lnj, jbb)</li>
        </ul>
        <p>This release fixes the following bugs:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fix AppImage build (jbb)</li>
          <li>Fix scrolling and item height problems in settings (jbb)</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Require Qt 5.12 and QXmpp 1.2</p>
        <p>Drop Ubuntu Touch support due to outdated Qt</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release type="stable" version="0.4.2" date="2020-04-02T00:00:00Z">
      <description>
        <p>This release adds the following features:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>ChatMessage: Do not display media URLs (lnj)</li>
          <li>ChatMessage: Add media URL copy action (lnj)</li>
        </ul>
        <p>This release fixes the following bugs:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fix roster not cleared when switching account (lnj)</li>
          <li>ChatMessage: Fix copy to clipboard function (lnj)</li>
          <li>Fix scroll indiciator not overlap message on the right edge (fazevedo)</li>
          <li>Fix upload issues (fazevedo)</li>
          <li>ChatPage: Clear message correction when sent (fazevedo)</li>
          <li>Fix roster sorting (lnj)</li>
          <li>Fix buttonTextColor deprecation warnings (sredman)</li>
          <li>Fix build with QXmpp &gt;= 1.0.1 (lnj)</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release type="stable" version="0.4.1" date="2019-07-16T00:00:00Z">
      <description>
        <p>This release fixes the following bugs:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fix SSL problems for AppImage (lnj)</li>
          <li>Fix connection problems (lnj)</li>
          <li>Keep QXmpp v0.8.3 compatibility (lnj)</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release type="stable" version="0.4.0" date="2019-07-08T00:00:00Z">
      <description>
        <p>This release adds the following features:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Show proper notifications using KNotifications (lnj)</li>
          <li>Add settings page for changing passwords (jbb, lnj)</li>
          <li>Add XEP-0352: Client State Indication (gloox/QXmpp) (lnj)</li>
          <li>Add media/file (including GIFs) sharing (lnj, jbb)</li>
          <li>Full back-end rewrite to QXmpp (lnj)</li>
          <li>Implement XEP-0363: HTTP File Upload and UploadManager for QXmpp (lnj)</li>
          <li>Use XEP-0280: Message Carbons from QXmpp (lnj)</li>
          <li>Use XEP-0352: Client State Indication from QXmpp (lnj)</li>
          <li>Check incoming messages for media links (lnj)</li>
          <li>Implement XEP-0308: Last Message Correction (lnj, jbb)</li>
          <li>Make attachments downloadable (lnj)</li>
          <li>Implement XEP-0382: Spoiler messages (xavi)</li>
          <li>Kaidan is now offline usable (lnj)</li>
          <li>Kaidan is able to open xmpp: URIs (lnj)</li>
          <li>New logo (ilyabizyaev)</li>
          <li>Show presence information of contacts (lnj, melvo)</li>
          <li>Add EmojiPicker from Spectral with search and favorites functionality (jbb, fazevedo)</li>
          <li>Highlight links in chat and make links clickable (lnj)</li>
          <li>New about dialog instead of the about page (ilyabizyaev)</li>
          <li>Add image preview in chat and before sending (lnj)</li>
          <li>Send messages on Enter, new line on Ctrl-Enter (ilyabizyaev)</li>
          <li>'Add contact' is now the main action on the contacts page (lnj)</li>
          <li>Elide contact names and messages in roster (lnj)</li>
          <li>Chat page redesign (ilyabizyaev)</li>
          <li>Display passive notifications when trying to use online actions while offline (lnj)</li>
          <li>Automatically reconnect on connection loss (lnj)</li>
          <li>Contacts page: Display whether online in title (lnj)</li>
          <li>Add different connection error messages (jbb)</li>
          <li>Use QApplication when building with QWidgets (notmart)</li>
          <li>Ask user to approve subscription requests (lnj)</li>
          <li>Remove contact action: Make JIDs bold (lnj)</li>
          <li>Add contact sheet: Ask for optional message to contact (lnj)</li>
          <li>Add empty chat page with help notice to be displayed on start up (jbb)</li>
          <li>Redesign log in page (sohnybohny)</li>
          <li>Add Copy Invitaion URL action (jbb)</li>
          <li>Add 'press and hold' functionality for messages context menu (jbb)</li>
          <li>Add copy to clipboard function for messages (jbb)</li>
          <li>Add mobile file chooser (jbb)</li>
          <li>Highlight the currently opened chat on contacts page (lnj)</li>
          <li>Remove predefined window sizes (lnj)</li>
          <li>Use new Kirigami application header (nicofee)</li>
          <li>Make images open externally when clicked (jbb)</li>
          <li>Use QtQuickCompiler (jbb)</li>
          <li>Display upload progress bar (lnj)</li>
          <li>Add text+color avatars as fallback (lnj, jbb)</li>
          <li>Remove diaspora log in option (lnj)</li>
          <li>Support for Android (ilyabizyaev)</li>
          <li>Support for Ubuntu Touch (jbb)</li>
          <li>Support for MacOS (ilyabizyaev)</li>
          <li>Support for Windows (ilyabizyaev)</li>
          <li>Support for iOS (ilyabizyaev)</li>
          <li>Add KDE Flatpak (jbb)</li>
          <li>Switch Android builds to CMake with ECM (ilyabizyaev)</li>
          <li>Improve Linux AppImage build script (ilyabizyaev)</li>
          <li>Add additional image formats in AppImage (jbb)</li>
          <li>Forget passwords on log out (lnj)</li>
          <li>Append four random chars to resource (lnj)</li>
          <li>Save passwords in base64 instead of clear text (lnj)</li>
          <li>Generate the LICENSE file automatically with all git authors (lnj)</li>
          <li>Store ubuntu touch builds as job artifacts (lnj)</li>
          <li>Add GitLab CI integration (jbb)</li>
        </ul>
        <p>This release fixes the following bugs:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fix blocking of GUI thread while database interaction (lnj)</li>
          <li>Fix TLS connection bug (lnj)</li>
          <li>Don't send notifications when receiving own messages via. carbons (lnj)</li>
          <li>Fix timezone bug of message timestamps (lnj)</li>
          <li>Fix several message editing bugs (lnj)</li>
          <li>Fix black icons (jbb)</li>
          <li>Fix rich text labels in Plasma Mobile (lnj)</li>
          <li>Small Plasma Mobile fixes (jbb)</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release type="stable" version="0.3.2" date="2017-11-25T00:00:00Z">
      <description>
        <p>This release adds the following features:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Added AppImage build script (#138) (@JBBgameich)</li>
          <li>Use relative paths to find resource files (#143) (@LNJ2)</li>
          <li>Source directory is only used for resource files in debug builds (#146) (@LNJ2)</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release type="stable" version="0.3.1" date="2017-11-20T00:00:00Z">
      <description>
        <p>This release fixes the following bugs:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fixed database creation errors (#135, #132) (@LNJ2)</li>
          <li>ChatPage: Fixed recipient's instead of author's avatar displayed (#131, #137) (@LNJ2)</li>
        </ul>
        <p>This release adds the following features:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Added Travis-CI integration (#133, #134, #136) (@JBBgameich)</li>
          <li>Added Malay translations (#129) (@MuhdNurHidayat)</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release type="stable" version="0.3.0" date="2017-08-15T00:00:00Z">
      <description>
        <p>This release adds the following features:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Added XEP-0280: Message Carbons (#117) (@LNJ2)</li>
          <li>Added XEP-0054/XEP-0153: VCard-based avatars (#73, #105, #119) (@LNJ2)</li>
          <li>Added file storage for simply caching all avatars (@LNJ2)</li>
          <li>New roster design - showing round avatars and last message (#118) (@LNJ2)</li>
          <li>New chat page design - showing time, delivery status and round avatars (#123) (@LNJ2)</li>
          <li>Switched to XMPP client library "gloox" (#114) (@LNJ2)</li>
          <li>Rewritten most of the back-end for gloox and partialy also restructured it (#114) (@LNJ2)</li>
          <li>(Re)written new LogHandler for gloox (Swiften had this already included) (#114) (@LNJ2)</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release type="stable" version="0.2.3" date="2017-06-19T00:00:00Z">
      <description>
        <p>This release fixes the following bugs:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>LoginPage: Remove material shadow (#113) (@JBBgameich)</li>
          <li>Kaidan was crashing since v0.2.2 when inserting a new message to the DB (@LNJ2)</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release type="stable" version="0.2.2" date="2017-06-19T00:00:00Z">
      <description>
        <p>This release fixes the following bug:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>RosterPage: Clear TextFields after closing AddContactSheet (#106) (@JBBgameich)</li>
        </ul>
        <p>This release adds the following features:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>RosterController: Save lastMessage for each contact (#108) (@LNJ2)</li>
          <li>Add database versioning and conversion (#110) (@LNJ2)</li>
          <li>Database: Add new roster row `avatarHash` (#112) (@LNJ2)</li>
          <li>CMake: Add feature summary (#109) (@LNJ2)</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release type="stable" version="0.2.1" date="2017-06-08T00:00:00Z">
      <description>
        <p>This release fixes the following bug:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Roster page: Fixed style: Now has contour lines and a cool material effect (@LNJ2)</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release type="stable" version="0.2.0" date="2017-06-06T00:00:00Z">
      <description>
        <p>This release adds the following features:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Add Roster Editing (#84, #86) (@LNJ2, @JBBgameich)</li>
          <li>Roster refreshes now automatically (#83) (@LNJ2)</li>
          <li>Contacts are now sorted (@LNJ2)</li>
          <li>Add unread message counters (#92, #101) (@LNJ2)</li>
          <li>Add LibNotify-Linux notifications (#90) (@LNJ2)</li>
          <li>Add custom JID resources (#82) (@LNJ2)</li>
          <li>Add XEP-0184: Message Delivery Receipts (@LNJ2)</li>
          <li>Disable stream compression by default (for HipChat/other server compatibility) (@LNJ2)</li>
          <li>GUI: Port to Kirigami 2 (#81) (@JBBgameich)</li>
          <li>User Material/Green Theme per default (@LNJ2)</li>
          <li>Login page: New design with diaspora* login option (#87) (@JBBgameich)</li>
          <li>Chat page: Slightly improved design (@LNJ2)</li>
        </ul>
        <p>This release fixes the following bugs:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>AboutPage: Fix possible closing of multiple pages (@LNJ2)</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1">
    <content_attribute id="social-chat">intense</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="social-audio">intense</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="social-location">intense</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="social-contacts">intense</content_attribute>
  </content_rating>
</component>
